[{"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What challenges do you anticipate if hired as our next Corporate Trainer, and how will you meet those challenges?", "answers": ["When starting a new job, you will always face new challenges. Career moves can be both challenging and exciting as they allow you to learn new skills and overcome challenges you haven't faced before. Discuss with your interviewer a couple of responsibilities in this Corporate Trainer role that will present a learning curve. What your interviewer will ideally be looking to hear is that you have a plan in mind for meeting and overcoming the challenges that you foresee. Perhaps this opportunity requires you to learn the details of a new industry, and you know that it will take some time to adjust. Be honest with the interviewer about the challenges you expect to face; however, focus most of your response on the action steps you plan to take to meet these challenges.", "\"As you can see from my resume, I have spent the last 10 years of my career in the healthcare field where I've really honed my craft in providing training to both front-line healthcare workers and back-end support staff. The biggest challenge for me will be entering the hospitality industry at your organization. While I am confident in my ability to design and deliver impactful training to any group of employees, coming into this role will require me to put a lot of focus into learning the jobs and staff at your organization. If hired as your Corporate Trainer, I would plan to spend as much time possible with front-line employees and leaders to learn the jobs I would be providing training for, their nuances, and highest needs for improvement.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "We need our next Corporate Trainer to have strong written communication skills. How would you rate your written communication skills?", "answers": ["Your interviewer will have a good indication of your verbal communication skills through your interview process, but because written communication skills are so important for the success of a Corporate Trainer at their organization, your interviewer is posing this question to you to get an idea of your strengths as a writer. As you rate your written communication skills, be sure to talk about your written projects from previous roles. Don't hesitate to talk about formal curriculum instructions you have written.  Even discussing clear and consistent communications in email and memos is important in this role, so talk about why taking the time to write clearly is important in your work. However you answer, make sure that your interviewer walks away knowing that written communications are essential to your work.", "\"My written communication skills are strong. As you can see in the portfolio I've provided, the written training sessions that I develop are clear, concise, and error-free. Any time that I write, I take time to proofread and even use a program like Grammarly to ensure that I avoid both grammar and spelling mistakes. I take this same approach when I draft other communications like internal memos and email communications as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "If hired as our next Corporate Trainer, how would you determine if a training program was successful?", "answers": ["In the end, the organization you are interviewing with wants to ensure that time and money put into employee training strengthens their workforce to meet business goals. They'll want to be confident in your ability to measure the success of the training programs that you will administer in this role. While you are aware that there are many ways to measure the success or failure of a particular training program, how you measure success may ultimately differ based on the type of training that you provide and who your audience is. As you answer, talk about the importance of using on-the-job measurements with a training session. Talk about your desire to solicit feedback from learners and leaders on the training that you provide and how you can utilize constructive criticism to your advantage.", "\"Any time that I can utilize key performance indicators to measure a training program's effectiveness, I do just that. If I'm training warehouse staff on being efficient on the job, I can utilize order fill times prior to and following the training as a measurement of the success of the training. If a training session I create utilizes a quiz or test, looking at the results of those is a way of determining the training's effectiveness, and I can adjust the program if needed. Sometimes, it is necessary to rely on more subjective data like feedback from those attending my training and their managers. Any time I conduct in-person training, I utilize a feedback form that has learners rate the content of the training and my delivery. I have used this feedback consistently over my career to improve.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "How do you assess learner performance after you deliver a training session to staff?", "answers": ["As a competent Corporate Trainer, you know that much of your work performance is benchmarked against the performance of your learners and the results they generate after attending your training sessions. The measurable results you can generate as a trainer are precisely how you will portray the value of your sessions and training programs. Assessing training is also equally important in making necessary improvements to the programs you design in the future. Talk to your interviewer about the framework you use to assess learner performance. Highlight the fact that you go into each training session with a clear understanding of the expected outcomes of the training. Be sure to show the interviewer that you consider the company's return on investment from your training. Express that you put great consideration into the company's most vital metrics when you assess learner performance.", "\"In my current position, I lean on the Kirkpatrick Model for assessing learner performance. This model has four levels: Reaction, Learning, Behavior, and Results. Level one is 'Reaction,' where I assess the degree to which participants find the training engaging and relevant. Level two is 'Learning,' where I assess the level of learner participation. At this stage, I observe the attitude, confidence, and commitment of the attendees. Level three is 'Behavior.' At this level, when the learners are back on the job, I look at the degree to which they apply what they learned during the training session. Last is level four, 'Results.' In this final stage, I assess the results of the training. Then, I track the results and provide a comprehensive report to the appropriate stakeholders. All of my sessions include post-training support and accountability, which results in a better ROI for the company and much stronger long-term results for the employees as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "If hired as our Corporate Trainer, how would you handle an employee that was being difficult or unruly in a training session?", "answers": ["In large group training sessions, there may come a time where an employee is being disruptive to other learners, and you will be responsible for curbing the behavior immediately as the trainer. Be very direct with your interviewer on how you would handle this situation. It is recommended to first make a general comment to the group in hopes that the difficult employee would get the hint. From there, more serious action should take place. This could include excusing the employee from the training if the situation called for it. Make sure your interviewer understands that you are a trainer that would not let things get out of hand in your training sessions. If you have a specific example of a time when you had an employee being difficult and you managed it effectively, don't hesitate to talk about how you handled the situation.", "\"First, I would use my best judgment about when to intervene, and if the employee was truly disrupting the learning of others, I wouldn't hesitate to call them out or dismiss them from the training. If the actions called for it, I would report it to their supervisor following the training. Last year, I had a very outspoken gentleman in a training session who was using foul language. I simply requested that we keep all conversations PG in nature and he was very quick to stop using the language that was making others uncomfortable. The direct approach worked. Another time a few years back, there were two employees that were laughing with each other, texting, and simply being too loud for others around them in a room of about 30 people. I warned them once in front of the group to please stop. When they continued again, I asked them to leave and let their manager know immediately. I take the learning opportunities that I provide to employees seriously and also expect that same respect out my learners at all times.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Our Corporate Trainer often meets with managers and supervisors to discuss upcoming training topics and approaches. Have you ever had difficulty communicating with a supervisor?", "answers": ["Possessing the skills to enhance communication in the workplace is a valuable asset, especially as a Corporate Trainer. When approaching this question, remember that the interviewer does not want to hear that you agree with everybody at all times. In a perfect world, you communicate well and get along with the leaders that you support at all times. However, this is not always realistic. A response like that fails to give the interviewer insight into your behaviors and communication style in the workplace.  What matters most is not that you have a perfect record with your leaders, but how you approach a situation in which you disagree with a leader. Demonstrate to your interviewer that you can collaborate well with your leaders, especially when choosing training approaches and deciding on upcoming training session topics. If you've ever experienced a time when it was difficult to communicate with a supervisor, tell a brief story that highlights your actions and the result of your communication approach.", "\"Yes, I have had difficulty with one particular manager that I supported training efforts for and it honestly took a lot of effort to focus my communications and make it a positive relationship. When I first started working with him, he wasn't very receptive to my ideas when we discussed new training for his staff. As I talked with others, I was told that he was an experienced leader who was very set in his ways. At that point, I knew I had to vary my approach with him and take a very analytical approach with hard data to prove why my thoughts would bring positive results to his group of employees. After he saw the results that similar groups were having with self-paced online training courses, he decided we could give it a try, and what he saw in the months following the new training path impressed him.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What tools do you us in your work to ensure that you stay organized and on track with your work?", "answers": ["As a Corporate Trainer in this role, you will often be juggling multiple training projects at one time. This means that you will be dealing with the planning, development, scheduling, and conducting of multiple projects at once, all at different stages of the process. This will require a very organized and detailed approach to your work, and your interviewer is looking to hear how you stay organized in your work. While there is no right or wrong answer to this question, your interviewer will want to hear that you have an effective method in place for staying organized and on track with everything that you are working on at the same time. Before your interview, be sure to prepare how you will speak to your method for staying organized, and make sure to highlight the tools and resources you use in doing this.", "\"Ensuring that all of the projects I have going at once stay on track can seem like a full-time job sometimes, but using my Outlook calendar and tasks functions help me to ensure that I am meeting deadlines, scheduling training on time, and ensuring that drafts of projects go out for approval on time. I've also started recently using the Microsoft 365 Project Management tool and have customized it to fit my needs for planning training sessions for staff.  Being kind of old school, I also always carry around a pencil and paper when I'm away from my office to jot important notes down, and I always have a daily to-do list written on my desk.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Describe a time when you had to sell an idea or change someone's mind regarding instituting a new training for staff.", "answers": ["As a Corporate Trainer with this organization, you will likely come across situations where you have to influence others to make a decision. The people you will need to influence and persuade will often include high-level leaders within the organization. Your answer should be based on your own past experience and knowledge. Your interviewer will want to learn that you were collaborative and respectful and that you can bring this same collaboration and mutual respect to their team. Furthermore, they will also want to hear that you want what's best for the employees in the end. A strong answer will include an example supported by a measurable outcome.", "\"I've always been a firm believer that monotony can be one of the biggest hindrances in the training of staff, so I'm a huge proponent of varied training to include multiple media sources, hands-on training, and guest speakers. This helps keep learners engaged instead of simply viewing a PowerPoint presentation. Last year, I wanted our Chief Financial Officer to speak at a training I was developing for nurses on wise use of company resources. I thought that the CFO could speak to how wasting resources impacts the organization's bottom line and where that can potentially trickle down. At first, the CFO wanted me to handle that discussion with the nurses I'd be training. I had to convince her that her first-hand insight would have the biggest impact on the front-line staff, and she wholeheartedly agreed to participate in the training.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What training program did you develop that you are most proud of? Talk about how it impacted you and those that put it to use.", "answers": ["In looking to bring you aboard as their next Corporate Trainer, your interviewer wants to hear that you take pride in your work. This question allows you the opportunity to show that. When interviewers ask about your accomplishments, they want to know what achievements you consider worthy of praise and why. Before your interview, think back on the project that makes you proud. Be able to describe the work that you put into it and the great results that came from it. If possible, make sure that your answer to this question closely matches this role.", "\"When I took over as the Trainer for a sales-driven retail organization, sales were at an all-time low, and my role was new to the company. During my interview process and upon being hired, it was emphasized that effective sales training would be at the top of my list in the first year on the job. In my initial weeks on the job, it didn't take long to learn that our sales team didn't have the overall drive to succeed that is seen at most other large retail outlets. Right away, I knew that my training needed to focus on motivational factors. Over the next few months on the job, I worked closely with the sales leadership team in creating mission-driven goals and values for their team that had never been defined before. With them, we created a list of missions and values that included the importance of the sales team to the organization and how to define success in the sales roles within the organization. When the training started, it was well-received by all. In the months following, overall sales numbers started to slowly increase and over time, our sales staff retention numbers increased significantly.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Give an example of a time when you successfully mentored a fellow colleague. What did you do that made it successful?", "answers": ["As a successful Corporate Trainer in this role, you will be working with and leading a team of training and development specialists. As part of your leadership duties, you will be expected to train and mentor them through the programs that you create. To be an effective mentor, your interviewer will be looking for you to highlight the skills that make you an effective mentor. Before your interview, be sure to think of an example of a time when you proved your ability to communicate effectively, listen attentively, share ideas willingly, and offer words of encouragement to the staff that you mentor.", "\"I take great pride in mentoring my colleagues through the programs that we develop. It's a key part of my job. It is important to mentor my team to get them on board with my overall philosophies on training. To mentor my team, I would openly seek their input. I would ask about their experiences and listen to their feelings concerning their mentoring needs. I would then share with them my plans and goals for each training session we would be developing. I would consistently monitor their work and observe the direct training they would provide to give them the best feedback and mentoring experience possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "How do you keep up with new developments and trends in employee training and development?", "answers": ["If asked this question during your interview, be sure that your interviewer is looking to hire a Corporate Trainer that can bring innovative training ideas to their organization. You know that your job is to maintain and increase productivity through employee development. You are a leader who has the opportunity to influence internal teams and implement and facilitate programs to help employees do their jobs and meet company expectations. As such, your interviewer wants evidence that you are passionate about bringing the most up-to-date ideas and development opportunities to their valued employees. Give the interviewer specific examples of the action steps you take to continue learning and growing your knowledge as a Corporate Trainer. Don't hesitate to talk about the journals you read and subscribe to and any professional organizations that you belong to. Feel free to talk about any recent training or seminars you have attended to give your interviewer the sense that you embrace your own career development.", "\"The world of corporate training, development, and employee education is always improving, which excites me! For that reason, I lean on a variety of online resources, such as blogs and podcasts. I also follow a few thought leaders on Medium and subscribe to LinkedIn Learning, which allows me to stay current while also training myself on new skills related to teaching and educating others. Additionally, I keep up with trends and new developments by keeping in close contact with other corporate training professionals in my network that I know and trust. Together, we discuss current trends and creative ideas to help us accomplish our goals as trainers. I am always open to learning new resources if you have any specific recommendations!\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Have you ever provided training to director level or C-Suite leaders? If so, what aspect did you enjoy most, and what did you find most challenging?", "answers": ["Even though it can be intimidating to train a group of high-level leaders, this could be a part of the role of the next Corporate Trainer at this organization. Your interviewer wants assurance that you are confident enough in your training abilities and presentation skills to deliver an effective training session, regardless of the seniority of the people you are training. If you have direct experience in providing manager, director, or even higher levels of training, be sure to talk in detail about the materials you presented and be open and honest about what aspect you enjoyed and what you found to be challenging. Be sure to talk about the size of the group that you presented to and how you handled the entire training to give your interviewer the sense that you can handle providing leadership training at their organization.", "\"Last year, I was tasked by my organization's CEO to present a training on diversity and inclusion in the workplace to our senior-level management team. I was asked to put this together on pretty short notice. To start the process, I discussed with our CEO to understand his goal for the training. Knowing that he wanted to help build awareness among the leadership staff on the benefits of a diverse and inclusive workforce, I was able to pull some great materials and information and put together a great presentation for our senior leaders. I presented the information at a monthly meeting that the group had and was given 30 minutes. Knowing that the information would generate great discussion, I planned my presentation for 20 minutes, and the open time at the end was left open for the group of 12 people to discuss questions and thoughts. While I was initially nervous about doing this with the team, it ended up working out great and my CEO was very happy with the results. I would say the most challenging piece was tailoring my presentation to a leadership level, where they could take information and disperse it among their staff.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Do you have familiarity with performing skills gap analyses in your work as a Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["Your interviewer will be seeking to hire the candidate that has their mind focused on the ultimate goal of this role. That goal is ensuring that the workforce of their entire organization can meet or exceed all duties of their jobs. Because this goal is an almost unreal expectation, a Corporate Trainer is needed to help bring workers to a higher performance level. The first step in doing this is to conduct skills gap analyses to know where training is needed for staff. If you have direct experience in performing these analyses, talk openly about that experience and how it helped focus your work for a good cause. If you don't have hands-on experience, be sure to research what a skills gap analysis entails to be able to talk intelligently about them and how you will put them to use in this job.", "\"Yes, I am very familiar with conducting skills gap analyses and have been for many years in my time in the manufacturing industry. Keeping a consistent pulse on the skills of the workforce is vital. When I complete skills gap analyses for manufacturing roles like machinists, welders, and assemblers, I take a three-step approach. In the first step, I work with leaders to define the key skills and abilities necessary for a specific job. Then, I work to identify the current skill set of the employees within that job and do so through review of previous performance appraisals, interviewing managers, and talking with front-line employees. Last, I analyze where the gaps are and then create a training program to help fill the gap in knowledge or skills. Recently, a skills gap analysis found that a large number of our welders were lacking the skills to work within our online inventory management system. After some basic skills testing, I created online training for staff that helped them develop their knowledge and skills in this area. This simple yet effective training boosted production due to less time spent in working through the online system in between tasks.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Tell me about a time when you received negative feedback after a training session. What was the criticism, and how did you react?", "answers": ["After a busy and demanding day of training, the last thing you want to hear is negative feedback on your work. However, criticism can be beneficial if you learn how to accept the feedback and implement appropriate and timely changes. As a successful Corporate Trainer, you know it's essential to make regular improvements to your training materials and methods. By applying the information you receive through constructive feedback, you can ensure that your training sessions generate the best possible results. By posing this question to you, your interviewer wants to know how you sort through criticism. They also want to see evidence that you take feedback and apply it to improve your work performance. Knowing that no trainer is perfect, your interviewer wants you to be open and honest about a time when you received negative feedback and how you put that feedback to good use.", "\"When I first joined my current organization as their Corporate Trainer, I received criticism from a trainee in an anonymous post-training survey. The trainee said that it seemed I did not have an in-depth understanding of the manufacturing industry. This trainee was correct, and I felt a sting of embarrassment at first. I came to the role with a human resources background and previously worked in the logistics industry; however, I wasn't as knowledgeable in manufacturing as I could have been. I knew that this trainee's feedback was accurate, and it was my responsibility to improve so that I did not disappoint more trainees in the future. I quickly enrolled in a few courses, including Six Sigma for Beginners, Lean Manufacturing, Manufacturing Process, and Process Control. All of these were promoted by my organization and approved by my manager. I gained a much stronger understanding of manufacturing environments, operational best practices, business processes, and performance in a manufacturing environment through these courses. As a result, I felt much more confident that I could offer future trainees the best possible learning experience because I possessed a much stronger knowledge of their work environment and industry. The next time I facilitated the same training session, my lesson plans and delivery were much more in-depth, and I received a 100% feedback score from the trainees. It's never easy to receive negative comments; however, I will always consider helpful and honest criticism. I have learned to filter through feedback and listen to what is constructive. If hired as your Corporate Trainer, I will continue to use feedback as an opportunity to improve. Rather than taking feedback personally, I will look inward to understand further what I can do to improve. I will be proactive about implementing necessary changes and updates to my training sessions and identifying weaknesses so that the sessions are as impactful as possible for your deserving team.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What is the difference between employee training and employee development? As a Corporate Trainer, does your expertise land more on training or on development?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like your perspective on training and development and the subtle nuances between the two terms. They would also like to know which area you are best versed in. As a Corporate Trainer, your main focus will be on training, and your answer should focus on the training aspect. As you answer, be sure to discuss the differences between training and development. Speak about specific job-focused goals and group-focused training that works to improve on-the-job performance. Then speak to development focusing on individualized, long-term career goals for staff.", "\"I have a firm grip on the differences between training and development, and my expertise falls within staff training.  Training focuses on teaching a specific skill or process, typically to a group with a short-term goal. Development is a broader expansion, typically centered around more in-depth applications or working on personal and professional growth. Development tends to be focused on the long-term. I wholeheartedly believe that both training and development are critical components to an employee's success. However, my expertise lands more on the training side. Most of the training I have delivered is focused on enhancing a specific skill or element of knowledge. This focus will be a strong benefit to your organization since the primary focus of this Corporate Trainer role is to deliver focused training to your team. If the organization would like to add more long-term development-related activities, I can focus on additional personalized employee development solutions if needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What is your biggest weakness as a Training Specialist, and what are you doing to improve?", "answers": ["As you applied for and were invited to interview for this role as a Corporate Trainer, your interviewer has a very good sense of your strengths from your resume. Your interviewer is also aware that every candidate that they interview has weaknesses that show up in their professional life. If asked a question like this during your interview, remember that it is not meant to place focus on the ways you are weak or unskilled. The purpose of the question is for your interviewer to see if you are a future employee that has a strong character and who is working to improve professionally. Your interviewer also wants to ensure that your biggest weakness is not a vital part of your role as a Corporate Trainer with their organization. Pick one weakness and be sure you have an action plan in place for improvement. Be prepared to communicate your weakness without embarrassment. You should also clearly demonstrate how the lessons you learned and your effort to improve will add value to this organization.", "\"From the very start of my career in corporate training, I was always very nervous speaking in front of a large group of people. To this day, I can honestly say that I'm not in my prime comfort zone when in this position, but it has been something that I have been working on over the last ten years. Early in my career, I was coached by my director, and I've also taken an online course on public speaking as recently as three years ago.  I also listened to Dale Carnegie's 'The Art of Public Speaking.'  All of these have helped to continue to build my confidence when speaking in front of a large group.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "How do you make training fun and interactive for people as a Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["One large part of the struggle to provide meaningful training to employees that they can take with them to their jobs is ensuring that training is fun and interactive. Let's face it, a lot of employees don't take training as seriously as they should, and you as the trainer are tasked with making the training as engaging as possible. If asked this question during your interview, your interviewer is hoping to hear that you have some tricks up your sleeve when it comes to making training exciting for their staff. They are well aware that an engaged employee in training is one that learns and retains the most. As you prepare to answer this question, be ready to talk about ways to make both in-person and virtual training fun and interesting for staff.", "\"I'm a firm believer that my role is never to simply be a lecturer when training staff because I know that method just isn't effective in ensuring that employees actually take what they learn to their jobs. When I am conducting training in an in-person setting, I have several ways that I like to keep training fun and engaging. I never hesitate to tell stories because they help to relate the information to everyday life. If it works well for the particular training, I also like to incorporate games and participation from all of the learners. Of course, using visual aids is always important, as is allowing sufficient break times for people to stand up, stretch, and give their minds a break. I like to apply a lot of these same principles to online training courses that I develop. Using quizzes or quick tests to ensure retention of information helps keep learners engaged. Interactive training modules where learners have to manipulate things on their screen also helps make things fun and interesting during training, and I never hesitate to use these methods.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Talk about the various administrative duties you are responsible for in your current job. Why are these duties important to the overall success of the training that you provide?", "answers": ["Success as a Corporate Trainer involves many different administrative duties that often aren't the most exciting or gratifying duties. Your interviewer wants to hear that you take them seriously and that you understand their importance in the overall process. Some of these duties can include scheduling training sessions, booking space to provide training, preparing training materials, and keeping attendance records of training sessions. As you discuss the administrative duties that you handle in your current role and talk about why they're important in your job, keep in mind what administrative duties you will be handling in this role are. Before your interview, try to do as much research as possible on this role so you can speak to your ability to handle all duties required in this job to impress your interviewer.", "\"In my current position, I am responsible for all aspects of staff training including administrative duties. When I am planning a staff training, I book rooms for the training to take place. If we do them in-house, I book through our Outlook calendar. At times, we will conduct training offsite, and I have to then work with local hotels or conference centers to schedule. I also am responsible for putting together all training materials. This can include printing materials for learners and even scheduling meals during training sessions. I take the administrative part of my duties very seriously because the fine details are often what determines the overall success of a training session for staff. To keep myself organized and on track with all of my necessary tasks, I have a checklist of items that I walk through with each training that I coordinate, and all administrative tasks are included on that checklist.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "How do you determine when you need to seek the help of others when creating a new training program?", "answers": ["In asking this question during your interview, your interviewer will be looking to gauge both your critical thinking skills and how well you work as part of a larger team as a Corporate Trainer.  When put in a position to create meaningful and impactful training programs for any group of employees, you should take no shame in enlisting the help of others. Employees, managers, and leaders can often provide the greatest insight into training needs and the best methods for delivering training. Before your interview, put some serious thought into how you decide to enlist the help of others in the work that you do. If necessary, don't hesitate to talk about a time or two that you sought input from another person or group of people to ensure that a training program was successful.", "\"Throughout my career, I've never been hesitant to reach out to others for their expertise on specific training that I am putting together. While I am an expert on effective training methods, I am not always an expert on the subjects that I train on. This is particularly true for very job-specific training.  Take for example last year when I was tasked with providing training on new health insurance coverage laws to a group of billing staff and medical coders with my organization. Knowing this wasn't in my wheelhouse of expertise, I set a meeting with key leaders that could give me a good baseline of what the ultimate training goals were and a good place for me to start to begin hunting for relevant information on the training. While I did the legwork in putting the presentation together, it was vital for me to stay in contact with those leaders so they could have final input into the training. If hired as your next Corporate Trainer, I would look forward to partnering with all key leaders in creating great training programs for your staff.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What do you feel are good ways to motivate employees to take optional training courses?", "answers": ["As you are well aware as a professional Corporate Trainer, not all training programs are mandatory. Many that you help develop are optional. When optional training is considered for staff, you will be tasked with convincing staff that the training is well worth their time and effort.  In proposing this question to you, your interviewer is looking to hear that you are familiar with effective ways to convince staff to participate in voluntary training. Before your interview, be sure to think of the most popular ways for incentivizing employees in this situation, and if you have examples of ways you've done this in the past, don't hesitate to talk about them.", "\"Voluntary staff training has a purpose, and I think that there are many ways to promote staff participation in these. Since the lack of time is often a common reason that staff don't participate, I think it is important to set aside time during the normal workday and compensate staff for the voluntary training. Providing snacks, food, and beverages also helps to attract more people. I also think that in some instances, making the voluntary training mobile-friendly for workers on the go is a great way to promote participation in optional training. Another incentive could be providing gift cards or monetary payment for participation.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Are you able to work effectively in high pressure situations?", "answers": ["At times, a Corporate Trainer is required to work in high-pressure situations. Whether the stress is due to a massive workload or working hand in hand with the highest level of leadership at the organization, your interviewer will be looking for you to remain calm, cool, and collected when working in a pressure-packed situation. Before your interview, brainstorm some techniques that you use to work effectively in stressful situations. Be sure to talk about how you maintain a positive attitude and take care of yourself. Talk about the importance of staying organized and resourceful to work through stressful situations.", "\"Yes, I consider myself very competent in a high-pressure work environment and believe that I thrive here when most others struggle. In my current role, I am often juggling many projects at one time and working with leaders from throughout the organization who can be very demanding and want things done now. To help alleviate unnecessary stress in these situations, I make sure that I communicate timelines in a fair manner and always deliver on my word. When handling many tasks at once, I keep myself organized and on a schedule each day to ensure that no deadlines are missed. No matter how rough things get, I always keep a smile on my face and a positive attitude. I also don't hesitate to step away and take a walk to help refresh my body and mind.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "As a Corporate Trainer, how would you evaluate and measure the success of the training you would provide to our staff?", "answers": ["There are many different ways you can monitor and measure your performance, success, and impact as a Corporate Trainer. As you are aware, there are training-specific software programs built to track metrics. Meeting with managers, leaders and other stakeholders is also necessary to get an idea of the effectiveness of a training. On top of these methods, getting direct feedback from the learner through conversation and surveys is also very helpful. No matter how you answer this question, you need to ensure that your interviewer knows that you take the evaluation of your training programs seriously and that you take the necessary measures to improve them when needed. It's also important for you to note in your answer that success will look different in many training scenarios and this is dependent on your audience and the intent of the training.", "\"I evaluate and measure my success as a Corporate Trainer by comparing my results against the training session goals. For instance, if the session's objective is to help a sales team generate more leads, I will measure the sales teams' results one week, one month, and three months after our training sessions. When I create an online training program for a remote team, I use a program that offers automated tracking and keeps detailed records of each trainee's progress, including which lessons they speed through successfully and which lessons they seem to struggle with. Utilizing these tracking features, I can see when a trainee's progress slows, which allows me to encourage them or provide more clarity when needed. If I notice a pattern among the group in a specific module, I know this part of the training needs improvement. When I teach in-person workshops or sessions, I use feedback forms to check in with the trainees after each unit or lesson. These forms allow me to receive anonymous constructive feedback, and then I can adjust the lesson material as needed. Another method of evaluating the impact of my training sessions is to meet with the employees' manager to discuss whether their objectives were met, exceeded, or if they fell short after the training. My work as a trainer is never done, and I am eager to make continued improvements to my training plans. If hired for this role, I will continue to be diligent in improving my work and processes.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "How do you decide what gets top priority when scheduling your time and balancing training needs across an organization?", "answers": ["Prioritization can often be a major challenge for a Corporate Trainer, especially when you are being pulled in many directions. When you and your team are faced with many training needs, you may need to help your leaders decide which training topics should be addressed first. In asking this question, your interviewer wants to know that you are considerate with your schedule and know how to prioritize tasks according to the needs of the company, the team members, or other stakeholders. They also want to know the process you take to decide which tasks get your immediate attention. As you answer, provide evidence that you are calm under pressure and that you have a reliable framework for triaging tasks and training sessions when they may all seem urgent at first. Walk the interviewer through your prioritization process, showing that your approach is a good fit for their company culture.", "\"Typically, when I am prioritizing tasks or training session topics, I will use the MoSCoW model. I have been trained in Agile methodology and lean toward this model because it focuses on company goals and employee needs. If you are not familiar with this model, it takes into consideration what are the must-have, non-negotiable priorities, and those are always at the top of my list. Next comes the should-have, important things that add great value. Next in the prioritizations comes could-have items that have a small impact. Last are the initiatives that are not an immediate priority. When prioritizing work, I take into account what is most important first while also considering important deadlines. To stay on track and organized, I like to use the Trello project management tool to keep track of all the training tasks my department is handling.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Walk me through your education. How has it prepared you for this role as a Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["With this question, your interviewer is looking to hear how your education has prepared you for success as their next Corporate Trainer. Provide your interviewer with an overview of your highest level of completed education, including where you attended school and the credentials you received. You can also highlight awards or accolades you received for excellent performance. In addition to the formal education you received from your post-secondary program, think about the soft skills you have gained that will benefit you in this role. For instance, if you participated in many group projects in school, you could share how these experiences improved your ability to collaborate in group environments. When you walk the interviewer through your education and training, remember to discuss the learning opportunities and experiences most relevant to the position. If you have attended any recent training seminars or conferences that are directly applicable, you can talk about those too.", "\"As you can see from my resume, I have a Bachelor's degree in business and a minor in Human Resources. I graduated with a 3.8 GPA, which I am very proud to have earned. I worked full-time while going to school, so I learned a lot about time management and discovered that I work best under some degree of pressure. My early career path took me into an HR Generalist role, where I quickly found I gravitated towards the training and development of staff. Two years after starting as an HR Generalist, I pursued my Master's degree online in Learning Design and Technology at USC. This turned out to be the greatest move in my career because it has put me in a position to succeed as your Corporate Trainer. In this program, I was exposed to coursework in instructional design, media, assessment of training programs, and design of virtual learning environments. In my practice-oriented Capstone, I designed an online training for plastics manufacturing.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "If hired as our next Corporate Trainer, what is the training style you would bring to our staff?", "answers": ["Your training style describes how you present information, explain tasks, communicate expectations, and make connections with the attendees at your training sessions. As an experienced Corporate Trainer,  you have likely developed a preferred style for delivering your materials in an impactful fashion. Your interviewer will have their preferred training style, and their employees will have preferred learning styles. For this reason, you must express the ways that your training style will be a match for this organization and its staff. As you answer, try your best to show your flexibility. Training is fluid and, although you will embrace your unique style, you should also show that you are ready to succeed in various training environments. Take the time to describe your learning style to the interviewer, and be sure to express that, no matter your approach, you put high-quality learning standards first.", "\"I describe my training style as learner-focused. I am flexible, and I am cognizant of tweaking my approach to suit the learning style of those I am educating. As a Corporate Trainer, I consider myself a guide or facilitator rather than an instructor with a strict tone. I go into each training with established learning objectives, and I follow an agenda; however, I am as flexible as possible with the pace of the training session attendees. When training, I lean on tangible and measurable examples to support the learning material, and I ask for learner participation as much as possible. I believe that when learners are active participants, they absorb the material faster and more effectively. From my research, it seems that your organization is seeking a Corporate Trainer that is learner-focused rather than the type to give learner-passive lectures. I am confident that my flexible and high-quality training standards will meet the needs of your teams and the organization's objectives.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Why do you believe our organization needs to employ a Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["As a successful Corporate Trainer, you know that your role is significant on numerous levels. Now, your interviewer wants to know the specific value that you plan to bring to their organization, should you be hired for this role. There are numerous reasons an organization would put a Corporate Trainer to use with their workforce. These include improving the overall skillset of the workforce, showing staff they are valued, grooming staff for promotions, and ensuring that the workforce is nimble for future innovations. Rather than responding with generalizations, consider responding more specifically about you and your skills. Show the interviewer that you fully understand and embrace the ways your impact as a Corporate Trainer will benefit their organization. Make sure your answer is specific and customized to the hiring company's needs.", "\"As your Corporate Trainer, my work will help improve employee retention rates, which you have stated is a current concern for the organization. My training sessions will also have a positive impact on your bottom line. I have helped my current company improve employee retention rates by 25% this year, and we've seen a $200K boost in bottom-line earnings since introducing more sales-based training sessions. I will create and run these programs with a hyper-targeted focus on optimizing company profitability and employee loyalty. If I am hired as your company's dedicated Corporate Trainer, I will help improve the knowledge and skills of employees, who will then deliver positive improvements that result in greater productivity and profits. In this role, I can also generate a boost in work ethic, workplace safety, and reduce human resource concerns.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What qualities do you believe make a successful Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["A talented Corporate Trainer will be many things, including proactive, a clear communicator, and naturally able to make others feel comfortable in various learning environments. They are educators who can effectively motivate and inspire others. Take some time to think of the top 3-5 qualities you believe a Corporate Trainer should possess. Consider the traits of industry peers that you admire. Most importantly, think of the top qualities that you have worked hard to develop, making you an excellent candidate for this role.  As you answer this question, share with your interviewer a few of the qualities you believe to be most important for a Corporate Trainer to succeed. Explain that you possess these essential qualities and support your response with examples of how you emulate these characteristics. Then, be sure to connect these qualities by discussing how they will benefit the hiring company when they choose to hire you.", "\"There are certain qualities that a successful Corporate Trainer should bring to this role at your organization. I believe the most important qualities are being well-organized, being learner-focused, and being a direct communicator. These are skills that I have concentrated on developing over my 8-year career. I understand that this position takes organization and a great deal of discipline, which I have proven to deliver in my current role. Currently, I typically have five to ten training sessions in progress with various groups. This volume requires me to be very organized and detail-oriented. As an experienced Corporate Trainer, I also understand the importance of showing empathy and being patient with others while actively listening to their learning needs. Should I be chosen for this opportunity, I will continue to provide training sessions that are learner-focused rather than trainer-focused. Last, I am a strong communicator and believe that your company and its culture will benefit from my direct and honest communication style. My open and genuine communication approach allows me to give and receive feedback freely. I work hard to provide solid direction to employees along with clear expectations, which are traits that I know your company values in its team members.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "If a team member or colleague wasn't pulling their weight on a training project, how would you handle that situation?", "answers": ["Your interviewer will be expecting that you can lead and manage key stakeholders and colleagues throughout the design process of a training program. Whether it is due to an overloaded work schedule or simply not caring, you may run into a person that doesn't want to do their fair share of the work on a project. Your interviewer will want to hear that you are able to handle a situation like this with a direct approach. They'll also want to know that you can do so with respect and a forward vision for the project.  If you have an example of a time when you dealt with a colleague in a situation like this, don't hesitate to discuss how you handled it with ease and success.", "\"On any training development project, a true team effort is a must. Every person involved has a specific role to play, and I know mine. If a team member wasn't doing the necessary work or giving the necessary information, as a leader, I would first approach them directly in a one-on-one situation to restate my expectations for them as part of the project. I wouldn't place blame. I would listen to them and absorb what they are saying to me. Ultimately I would stay positive. I'd stress just how critical their involvement is to this project and that the project goes as the people driving it goes. I would also tell them if they lacked support in some way, then we would resolve that issue.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "As our next Corporate Trainer, you would be responsible for planning and leading large workshops for our staff. Are you comfortable in this setting?", "answers": ["To be effective in this role as the next Corporate Trainer, your interviewer will expect you to have the ability to plan and lead large group training sessions as this is the core of this role. If you can, talk about a specific time when you planned and delivered a training session for a large group of staff.  Walk your interviewer through the steps you take to prepare for this kind of workshop. Your ability to prove your confidence in handling a large audience is key as you answer this question.", "\"In all honesty, this was something that I dreaded early in my career as I had a fear of public speaking. But over time, I've gained a lot of confidence. For me, preparation is the key to successfully deliver training to large groups of staff. I make sure that I am confident in and knowledgeable about what I am presenting. I prepare ahead of time for questions that I think will be asked. Then, when it comes time to present to the staff, I like to focus on talking to one or two people at a time within the crowd. This was a technique that I learned from a former colleague, and it works well for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Do you have any experience in handling a training budget?", "answers": ["If your interviewer poses this question during your interview, you can be sure that you will be responsible for managing a training budget that will need to be spread throughout the entire organization. If you do have direct experience in managing a budget on the job, talk about as many details as you can and speak to how you effectively used the funds most efficiently.  If you don't have experience in directly managing a budget, that is okay as long as you can discuss how to effectively do so. Whether you have direct experience or not, be prepared to talk about the importance of effectively assessing the training needs of the organization to spend dollars wisely. Don't hesitate to talk about new and innovative ways to save money on impactful training opportunities for staff.", "\"I do have experience managing a small annual training budget in my current role. If I understand correctly from our conversation today, I'd be responsible for a much larger budget with this organization, and I am ready to take on that challenge. Successfully managing a training budget comes down to putting money to use in the most efficient and impactful way. To do this here, I would work with frontline leaders and managers to determine the most crucial training needs of the organization. When that assessment is done, I can then begin researching how to utilize the budget to its maximum potential. Part of my research will be looking into new and innovative ways of thinking when it comes to training your workforce. This will include looking into creative learning management systems designed for your industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Do you have a favorite job category or experience level that you like to provide training for?", "answers": ["If a question likes this comes up during your interview, your interviewer is simply looking to hear your passion for working with employees in a specific job or experience level. If you love to work with new, entry-level staff to help get them up to speed in a new job, talk passionately about why that appeals to you. If you have experience and love training supervisors and managers, talk about why you love working with that level of employee.  No matter how you answer, just remember that your interviewer is looking for you to have sound reasoning and a passion for providing training in a professional setting.", "\"I have always had a passion for training front-line supervisors in how to be effective leaders. Having been trained in leadership myself, I'm a big fan of passing along my own knowledge in this area and then seeing leaders put the philosophy to use in the leadership of their teams. I can't count the number of times that I've had newer supervisors and managers thank me for the training I've provided them months down the road. They've been very open about how my training has transformed how they lead people and how much more productive their teams have become since. I'm a firm believer that front-line supervisors and managers have a huge impact on the performance of the overall workforce of an organization, and I tailor my training to have this same impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Describe your communication style. How has it benefited you in your work as a Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["Effective communication throughout the training process is crucial for the success of a Corporate Trainer. In addition to being comfortable in your communication with learners during a training session, you also need to prove your ability to communicate with all other leaders that you will work with in this role. Your interviewer wants to have a sense of how effectively you communicate.  As you answer, describe how you lead conversations with subject matter experts, cross-functional stakeholders, team members, and learners. Your interviewer will want to hear that your communication style fits well in the environment in which you work.", "\"I would call myself a diplomatic communicator. I like to see a situation from all sides as much as possible. When it comes to developing training sessions, I begin with the end in mind. The best way to do this is by gathering information from everyone involved, especially those who can provide the perspective from and about the learners I will be training. I wasn't always like this, especially growing up. However, I realized that to become more effective at work, I have to further develop my interpersonal skills. It has helped me to become a more charismatic person. I now have an easier time persuading and collaborating with others.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "What are you most looking forward to in this role as our next Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["Your interviewer asks this question to assess whether you can fulfill new responsibilities in their organization and whether you fit in well with their culture. When formulating your response, align the responsibilities and opportunities at your current role with those of the role you're applying for. Assure your interviewer that you've done your research on the job and the culture by speaking about what makes you excited for the new job. No matter how you answer this question, be sure to speak with passion, as that will be one of the top qualities they will be looking for in the candidate that they hire.", "\"Over the last six years, I've been able to hone my skills as a Corporate Trainer in the manufacturing industry.  My current role has given me a lot of opportunities to broaden my skill set in working with union trade workers and leadership. However, I feel there's not much upward mobility given the small size of the business and industry that I work in. In this role, I am looking forward to expanding my skill set and working with and providing training to many different groups of employees. I am a person that thrives on challenge, and the challenge here is what I would be most looking forward to.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Why did you aspire to take a career path as a Corporate Trainer?", "answers": ["This question provides an opportunity to show your passion for the role and why you think you're a good fit. Before your interview, be sure to research the organization's mission, vision, and core values and illustrate how your values align with theirs. To get a true sense of your passion as a Corporate Trainer, a successful answer will also talk about what ultimately drove you into this career field. No matter how you answer, speak from the heart as you passionately describe what led you directly to this interview.\n\nFor exampler: \"As you can see from my resume, I've taken a very unique career path into the training world. Following my Bachelor's degree program, I gained some great experience as an HR Generalist for three years. In this role, I was always most happy when conducting new employee orientations and at that point, I knew that working as a Corporate Trainer was my dream job. To pursue this passion as a career, my next step was the Crew Trainer position I took in the retail industry. The four years in that role have prepared me with the hands-on training I will be providing to the employees at your organization. If hired for this role, you'll quickly find that I have a passion for bettering the workforce and helping them become as competent as possible in their work.\"", "\"As you can see from my resume, I've taken a very unique career path into the training world. Following my Bachelor's degree program, I gained some great experience as an HR Generalist for three years. In this role, I was always most happy when conducting new employee orientations and at that point, I knew that working as a Corporate Trainer was my dream job. To pursue this passion as a career, my next step was the Crew Trainer position I took in the retail industry. The four years in that role have prepared me with the hands-on training I will be providing to the employees at your organization. If hired for this role, you'll quickly find that I have a passion for bettering the workforce and helping them become as competent as possible in their work.\""]}, {"topic": "Corporate+Trainer", "question": "Are you fluent and adaptable when it comes to learning new computer programs and software?", "answers": ["The corporate training field has become much more technology-driven. If hired to be their next Corporate Trainer, you will likely be using a variety of new systems and programs, and your interviewer wants to ensure that you will come in with the ability to learn and master these quickly. Many employers have their own customized email programs, websites, and learning management systems in which you will need to be effective and efficient. As you answer this question, reiterate that you have excellent computer skills and don't hesitate to give examples of the variety of programs that you have worked with throughout your career.", "\"I am very computer literate and am confident in my ability to learn any program required for this role quickly. In my current role, I work in the Microsoft Office suite and am skilled in word processing, Excel spreadsheets, and creating unique PowerPoint presentations. I also have experience working with a few different email systems. I have hands-on experience with a couple of learning management systems. In my current role, I use the Cornerstone Learning system. Within the system, I build new online training for staff and manage all quarterly and annual training tracking for staff. I have the ability to customize within this system. I also have some experience working in the TalentLMS program.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Describe a project you worked on that had significant impact.", "answers": ["Think back to a school or work-related project that had a significant impact. Perhaps the outcome of the project led to changes in the organization or a new way of doing things. Or, maybe you worked on a project to support a community initiative to help those in need. Describe the project, your contribution, and the impact. Your response will help the interviewer see your ability to work with others and contribute to a significant purpose.", "\"In one of my business classes I worked on a project for a delivering company which aimed to improve their delivery times. The ultimate goal was to bolster the reputation of their customer service. As part of the project, we looked at the factors that were affecting their delivery times such as traffic, long breaks, and too many deliveries on a route. Ultimately we were able to help this company address the areas of concern, and improve their delivery times.\"", "\"I think it is important for everyone to give back to the community when they can, so I always look for community service activities. I have participated in clothing and food drives, cleaning up the neighborhood, and hosted free activities for children. I believe all of these efforts have significant impact on our community.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "How will this internship prepare you for your career goals?", "answers": ["Choosing the right internship can be a challenge, but less so when you have your career goals lined up. The interviewer wants to know why you are applying for this particular internship. Your response will allow them to determine if you've done your research about the company and if your career goals align with the internship opportunity. Share how you think the role will strengthen specific skills, give you exposure to other careers or professionals, provide you with on-the-job experience, or allow you to get your foot in the door at your dream company. Whatever your reason is, share it with enthusiasm and hope!", "\"As a business major, I've dreamed of working for a company that would allow me to build my skills in logistics. After doing my research, I know that your company is a leader in this field and employs some of the top graduates from around the country. I'm excited about this opportunity because I will have a chance to work with the most advanced technology, a diverse group of talented employees, and work for a company that is highly reputable in the community.\"", "\"My HR education has given me the knowledge to work as a generalist. This internship will allow me to get hands-on experience in recruiting, which is directly aligned with my career goals. I'll be able to learn how to find candidates and work with clients from a leader in the staffing field.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "How do you handle problems that might arise?", "answers": ["There may be times when problems might arise on the job for any given reason that might affect your ability to perform or require your full attention. The interviewer wants to know about your problem-solving skills and that you will not become overwhelmed if/when problems occur. When problems arise, stress does too. Explain how you react during these times and how you maintain your stress level.", "\"I understand that every day will not go smoothly on the job. When a problem arises, my first step is to gather as much information as I can about the problem so I can figure out the best way to resolve it. I manage my stress by being proactive about a solution. That way I don't become overwhelmed.\"", "\"I handle problems by understanding the issue, taking immediate action, and asking for assistance if I need to.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Do you have any volunteer or community service experience?", "answers": ["Many companies take pride in giving back to the communities they serve. You may even notice articles and photos on the company's website that show their presence in the community. The interviewer wants to know if you have experience volunteering as well. The good thing about volunteering is that you not only help those in need, but you can use your experience on your resume to demonstrate your skills. Express your passion for serving the community and also mention any skills you've acquired by doing so.", "\"I think it is important for everyone to give back to the community when they can so I always look for community service activities. I have participated in clothing and food drives, cleaning up the neighborhood, and have hosted free activities for children. I believe all of these efforts have a significant impact on our community.\"", "\"I enjoy helping those in need and have participated in many volunteer activities. From these activities I've learned how to coordinate and plan events which are skills I plan to offer during my internship.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["When an interviewer asks an open-ended question like this, it can be difficult to know where to begin...and end! This question haunts many individuals who may accidentally go a little too in-depth into their personal lives. It happens. Keep your reply light, and work relevant. Share how you became interested in your career path and why you are looking forward to this internship. This question is an excellent opportunity to describe yourself by discussing the strengths and qualities you bring that align with the company's needs.", "\"I am excited about graduating with my degree in human resources. I enjoy HR work and I can't wait to help employees feel confident about their benefits and other job-related advantages. Outside of work, I enjoy training for triathlons. Getting outside and training helps me release stress and stay focused while at work. I'm excited for the potential to learn and grow with your organization.\"", "\"I've always wanted to do work that helps others, but I didn't want it to be in the healthcare field. Pursuing my degree in human resources has shown me so many ways that I can help others and I am so excited to become an expert in the field.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What are you passionate about?", "answers": ["You probably have many passions. The interviewer is trying to gauge your connectivity to this work, as well as get a sense of your strengths. It is always a good idea to provide a response that aligns with the job requirements or company culture so make sure you take some time to learn about the company. If you are unsure about how to answer this question, here are some examples:\n\n-Helping others\n-Solving problems\n-Healthy living\n-Family and friends\n-Art\n-Traveling\n-Becoming a leader", "\"I am passionate about pursuing a leadership role in my industry. I see myself one day running operations and making executive decisions so I am working hard to carve out my path towards achieving this goal.\"", "\"I am passionate about helping and protecting others. This is the reason why I chose this career path. I also volunteer in the community to assist those in need and do my part to make the world a better place to live and work in.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What has been your most rewarding accomplishment?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear about something you are proud of. If you have an accomplishment related to the job or the company, this would be a great example to share. In your response, be sure to mention how it relates to the position or how it has prepared you for it.\n\nIf you don't have a work-related accomplishment, that is ok too. Share the details of your accomplishment but more importantly, share why it made you proud. Perhaps it allowed you to put new skills to test, or you overcame something challenging. Or maybe your accomplishment had a special meaning to you. Whatever your reason, be sure to express it to the interviewer.", "\"My greatest accomplishment so far has been getting into the college of my dreams. I knew it was a hard school to get into so I worked really hard in high school to maintain a high GPA and also participated in activities that would prepare me for a future career. It was stressful at times, but I was so proud when I received my acceptance letter.\"", "\"My greatest accomplishment so far has been my promotion to assistant manager at the retail store I previously worked at. I started off as a sales clerk but learned the job quickly and worked extra hours whenever I could. I became the youngest member of the management team.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What excites you the most about this internship?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are excited about an internship with the company. Of course you will be building your skills and gaining exposure to the workforce, but share the things that excite you most about the opportunity. Perhaps this is your first job, or maybe it is the networking opportunities, working with experts, or the desire for permanent employment. Share your response with enthusiasm.", "\"Working for your company has been a goal of mine since I started pursuing my degree. Your company is a leader in the industry so I would love to learn from the best and hopefully earn a permanent role if possible.\"", "\"The most exciting aspect about this internship is the ability to use the skills I've obtained from my degree. The internship will boost my abilities and my confidence to step into the real world and start earning a living.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Describe a time where you demonstrated your leadership skills.", "answers": ["In this question, the interviewer is looking to hear about a specific example that demonstrates your solid leadership skills. Before the interview, think about previous experiences where you did more than what was expected of you to contribute to the overall success of a project. If you can tie this example back to the leadership qualities you'll bring to the internship, the interviewer will surely be impressed.", "\"I've taken the lead on several class projects. One time, in particular, was for a project that required my team to create a presentation for the class. I decided to take the lead because I enjoy seeing different parts come together as a whole. I made sure everyone finished their assigned areas of the presentation on time, and I also put the final presentation together. The project was well received.\"", "\"I've taken the lead on community projects such as car washes and fundraisers. I learned how to coordinate, assign duties, plan, as well as manage the vendor. I will definitely be able to use these skills in an internship for your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What skills can you offer our company?", "answers": ["This question is a good example of why it is crucial for you to review the job description in detail before your interview, even for an internship. Think about the areas you excel in or jobs you've had. In your response to the interviewer, share your strongest skills and how you will use them in this organization.", "\"Working in retail, I developed strong customer service skills. I was also good at cold calling, and I know both these skills are mentioned in the job description for this internship. I know the role here is a slight step up in my current responsibilities, but I'm looking for growth, and also a new way to contribute to a team.\"", "\"My greatest skills are all customer-related. With a reputation for good customer service, I can offer these skills to help lighten the load of other team members and I'll be dedicated to providing the level of service that your company is known for.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "How do you respond to negative feedback?", "answers": ["Whether it is a permanent role or internship, you will receive feedback on the job formally or informally. The interviewer wants to know how you respond to negative feedback. Be honest in your answer, but demonstrate that you can take negative feedback and learn from it. Also, show the interviewer that you can be professional and receptive to feedback that might not feel good to hear, but could lead to your improvement.", "\"Although I strive to work hard so I don't receive negative feedback, I know that it can only help me. I'd rather be given negative feedback so I know which areas I need to improve instead of not knowing where I'm falling short.\"", "\"As I am learning new skills and developing my career path, I welcome both negative and positive feedback. This tells me what areas I need to focus on so I can get more training, a mentor, or more experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Where do you see yourself in 5 years?", "answers": ["This question is used to determine if you have set any goals for yourself. The interviewer wants to see that you are thinking about the future and how you plan to progress over the next five years. Describe the career goals you have set for yourself and how you plan to achieve them. Some examples might be:\n\n-Attending graduate school to gain deeper knowledge in your career field\n-Working to move into a management position at this company\n-Developed a strong network of professionals in similar roles \n\nYou can also share your personal goals such as starting a family or buying a house.", "\"In five years I hope to be working for a company that allows me to use the business skills I've learned in college. I would like to be in a management position so I plan to learn the company inside and out by immediately finding a mentor, building my skills, and gaining as much experience and exposure as I can so I am a top contender for a supervisory role in the next five years.\"", "\"In five years I'd like to be attending graduate school part-time and working in my field of study. This will be challenging, but I know that a graduate degree will give me a deeper understanding of my field and I will be able to immediately apply this knowledge on the job.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What are your strongest subjects?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know where your strengths lie so they can make the connection between your learning and your potential work performance. Before responding, think about the qualities and requirements mentioned in the job announcement for this internship. Be honest in your response, but share your strengths in the subjects closely related to the job. If you excel in math or finance courses, share how your financial strengths can be beneficial to the organization.", "\"I've received my highest grades in my accounting courses. I have always enjoyed working with numbers and can see myself being happy in this career field. I would love to apply my accounting skills and knowledge within your organization to help your budget team out.\"", "\"My strongest subjects are my business courses. The subjects come easy to me and I am learning how different business functions work together to meet the needs of an organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "How would you rate your time management skills?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about your ability to manage your time and meet deadlines. Discuss how you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once. Think about how you manage your projects and daily tasks and how this will help you succeed in your internship. You can also give a numerical rating on a scale of 1 - 10 to describe your skill level.", "\"I would rate my time management skills as an 8. It can be challenging at times when I have tests and projects due, but I've learned how to focus my attention on the areas I'm weak in and not spend too much time on the tasks I know I can already do well.\"", "\"I think I'm proficient with time management. I keep track of my time by creating a list of tasks that I need to accomplish whether it is studying or projects or an assignment. This helps me stay on task and never miss a deadline.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Why did you choose your career path?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to learn your motivation and goals for pursuing your career path. This will show what you are passionate about and how you will fit into the organization. Perhaps you chose a field that will allow you to help others, or you chose a career that will allow you to work with numbers or data, or you wanted a career that would allow you to protect people and property. Whatever your reason, share how you decided on your career, the purpose you hope to fulfill, and the impact you hope to make.", "\"I've always been good with numbers so pursuing a career as an accountant was an easy decision. I understand how important an accountant is to a business or entrepreneur as I help them balance their books, ensure their funds are spent and received properly, and more importantly keep them out of trouble with the IRS.\"", "\"I initially started off as a business major. After I took my first accounting course, I discovered how much I enjoyed working with numbers and how good I was at it. So the switch to accounting as a career had to happen.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Tell us about your extracurricular involvement or how you spend your spare time.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how you spend your time outside of work because they are trying to get a sense of you outside of your professional life. Part of the intention of this question is to see your potential compatibility with the current team.  So be honest and show your passions. But still keep your answer succinct.", "\"I enjoy the arts and I am involved with theater at school. I've been in several plays and have also started writing my own projects.\"", "\"In my spare time, I enjoy doing physical activities such as biking, running, and swimming. It helps me stay healthy and works as a great stress reliever.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What is one area that you would love to learn more about professionally or personally?", "answers": ["As you are pursuing your degree, you have probably discovered other areas that you would love to learn about as well. Share your thoughts in full detail; your response to this question allows the interviewer to align your desires with opportunities within the company. If you are unsure what other areas you might want to learn about, you can also mention soft skills such as:\n\n-Leadership skills\n-Communication\n-Conflict resolution\n-Planning", "\"While finishing up my business degree, I've grown an interest in marketing. I know that companies rely on marketing efforts to create their brand recognition, gain customers, and get the word out about their products and services. I would love to learn more about this as I think it can benefit any company.\"", "\"I would love to learn more about building leadership skills. I hope to one day serve as a leader in an organization so it's important to start developing those skills now.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "How would your classmates or teachers describe you?", "answers": ["Before an interviewer or hiring manager decides to bring you onboard, they want to know what type of person you are to see if you are a good fit for the team. Be honest in your response and think about what others might say about you. Try to align your answers with the type of employee they are looking for based on the internship advertisement.", "\"My classmates and teachers would definitely say I'm helpful and a team player. On group projects, I often take the lead to make sure we finish on time and I am always willing to help others if they are struggling in class.\"", "\"My teachers would say I am punctual and dedicated.  I have never missed a class and do my best to maintain perfect attendance. A day missed could mean that I miss out on important lessons and I never want that to happen if I can help it.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What do you know about our company?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you have put some effort into learning about their company. You can find this information online through their website or by doing a Google search. Discuss with the interviewer what you discovered during your search. It is okay to ask the interviewer for more information about the company as well.", "\"From my research, I understand you provide services and products to customers in the XYX industry. Your range of services is broad which was one of the reasons I'd love to intern here. I would be able to contribute to the team across service sectors and get exposure to handling a variety of service areas and customers.\"", "\"I have conducted a great amount of research on this company before coming for my interview today. I learned that you provide a wide range of services for a diverse customer base. Is that correct? The one service that stood out to me was XYZ because it is directly related to my area of study in college.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Why do you want to intern here?", "answers": ["As you know, an internship helps you build skills and gain experience. But the interviewer wants to know if you are genuinely interested in an internship at this company. Use this opportunity to share the knowledge and experience you hope to take away from your time in this role, but also share why you chose this company. Perhaps they are a leader in the industry or employ the best of the best; share your reason and be sure to mention what skills you will bring to the organization. Your response will help the interviewer align your desires with the opportunities in the organization.", "\"This company is a leader in the XYZ industry. An internship would allow me to build on my skills and work with some of the best people in the field. I would love to be able to bring my skills into the organization and learn new ones from a reputable company like this one.\"", "\"I know that your organization does X and Y which are skills that I'd like to build on. I've read about the work you are doing in this area and would love to contribute to a cause of this magnitude while gaining skills and hands-on experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What makes you a great candidate?", "answers": ["This question offers you the opportunity to go beyond your education and experience to articulate what sets you apart from other candidates. If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask classmates or teachers what sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived. It is also a good idea to think about the courses you enjoy and excel in. Consider too, the extracurricular activities you pursue. If you've ever been recognized for a particular skill, or have received recognition for making a significant impact on a project, feel free to mention this in your response if it relates to the internship.", "\"I believe I am a great candidate because I am eager to learn and eager to help. From the first day forward I will give 100% as I am grateful for the opportunity to work for a highly reputable organization like this one. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\"", "\"I am a great candidate for this internship because I am performing at the top of my class. I know I would be valuable to the team and bring a fresh perspective of things with the knowledge I've obtained.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Describe a difficult decision you've had to make and the outcome.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you are someone who can make difficult decisions on the job. Describe a situation where you've had to make a tough decision. Share your thought process, feelings, and the outcome.", "\"I got accepted into both of my top choices for college and had to make the decision on which one I would attend. Both schools offered the program I was interested in but one was located out of state and it would be my first time away from my family. I decided to go with the school out of state because I ultimately wanted to experience new things. I was scared and unsure, but it was the best decision I've made.\"", "\"Deciding on my major was one of the most difficult decisions I've ever had to make. I'm interested in so many subjects and having to choose one area of focus felt like I was being boxed in. I ended up choosing the major that I was most interested in and could see myself doing long-term.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Do you prefer working with a team or alone?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know what workplace setting allows you to be the happiest and most productive. Talk to the interviewer about your preference when it comes to teamwork or working individually. Be sure to avoid pigeonholing yourself into one particular scenario (IE: I only like to work by myself).", "\"I don't have a preference and enjoy working in both settings. However, during my internship, I hope to work with teams or other individuals often so that I can learn in a dynamic environment.\"", "\"I've learned that I can be productive in any setting. I truly don't have a preference.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Tell me about your ability to work under pressure and handle stressful situations.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you are someone who can handle stress on the job. Explain how you manage stress and your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I always remain calm and look for ways to be more efficient. For instance, if there is a deadline, I will determine what can be done to meet that deadline. I will write down the steps to ensure successful completion and get started right away instead of procrastinating. I know that stressful situations are bound to happen in the workplace and I will remain professional and willing to adjust when I need to.\"", "\"I know that stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest. I take good care of myself and prioritize my work to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels and it has allowed me to complete my degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Describe your approach to learning new skills.", "answers": ["Employers are always looking to hire lifelong learners who are open to expanding their skill set, especially during an internship. Demonstrate to the interviewer that you are curious and eager to learn. This will also communicate your excitement about being selected for an internship at this company.", "\"Even though I am almost done completing my Bachelor's degree, there is so much more I'm excited to learn about. I'm excited to learn from the members of this organization as I know your company employs the most talented individuals in the industry.\"", "\"I believe learning is something you never stop doing. In addition to obtaining an internship, I plan to continue building my skills by finding a mentor, attending conferences, and training opportunities on the job.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What is your definition of hard work?", "answers": ["This may seem like a trick question since there is no specific answer. The interviewer wants to know that you will be a productive member of the team, and not someone failing to pull their weight. Some keywords you might mention in your response can include: \n\n-Sacrifice\n-Dedication\n-Teamwork\n-Results-driven\n-Focus\n\nYour response will tell the interviewer if you are a good fit.", "\"My definition of hardwork means going above and beyond to achieve a goal. This might mean working extra hours, staying focused on tasks, or helping others on the team.\"", "\"To me, hard work means putting forth the extra effort and doing more than what's required without my boss telling me to.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Do you have any questions for me?", "answers": ["You should always have questions prepared to ask the interviewer.  Before your interview, do some research on the company and write down any questions that you'd like to ask. This is a good opportunity for you to learn about the internship, the company, the team, or anything else you'd like to know. \n\nThis shows that you are interested in the position and fully engaged in the interview process.", "\"Yes. Can you tell me about the other team members I will be working with? What are their roles? Also, will there be an opportunity for me to be exposed to other areas in the organization? I'm willing to help out wherever I can.\"", "\"What do you love most about this company? Also, what skills or experience can I offer that would lighten the load during my internship?\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know the areas you struggle with, but they also want to hear how you manage that struggle. This can be school or work-related. You can be candid in your answer, recognizing that you aren't great at something and acknowledging your need to improve. However, pick weaknesses that are not core skills for this position. Be sure to have an action plan in place for improving on this weakness. \n\nPerhaps you are watching TED talks to gain skills in a particular area, reading the latest and greatest book on the subject, or maybe you are taking a seminar at a nearby community center. Identify your weakness and the action taken for improvement. We are all human with our weaknesses, so don't be afraid to share yours!", "\"I believe I could improve on some technical skills including Excel and PowerPoint. Currently, I am somewhere between beginner to intermediate level. However, I would be more comfortable at an advanced level to help me develop more effective reports. I have enrolled myself in an evening/weekend workshop for the next six weeks. I'm looking forward to seeing how stellar my skills are after that course and how I will be able to apply my skills on the job!\"", "\"Everyone has weaknesses.  I tend to be too nice sometimes, and have a hard time saying no, and because of that, I can put a lot of undue pressure on myself.  To get better in this area, I have to remind myself that it is ok to have boundaries and to be firm about them.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "Who is someone you consider a great leader or mentor?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know who has had a positive impact on your life or someone you hold in high regard. While your response can pertain to your personal or professional life, it is a good idea to keep it professional and mention someone who has had a positive influence on your career path or education.", "\"My instructor for my human resources course has been a great mentor for me. She has really opened my eyes to the vast opportunities in the field and has shared her own personal journey in the industry. This has motivated me to think about my future and be more intentional about my other college courses.\"", "\"My basketball coach was a great leader for me in high school. He taught us how to persevere through challenges and that with hard work and dedication, we could win at anything we set our minds to. His encouraging words have stuck with me.\""]}, {"topic": "Intern", "question": "What would make this internship successful for you?", "answers": ["Understanding your expectations and goals is important for both you and the interviewer. Don't be afraid to express what you'd like to gain from this experience even if you are unsure if it is possible. Tell the interviewer about your hope to earn a permanent position, experience, exposure, or knowledge if these are the things that would deem the internship successful to you. The interviewer will be able to give you an idea on whether or not your goals are attainable and maybe even advice on how to ensure your internship is successful.", "\"Earning a permanent role in this organization would make this opportunity successful for me. I hope to learn what it takes to get hired and be a valuable employee for the team.\"", "\"Success in this internship for me would mean that I walk away with a deeper understanding of the industry, the ability to network with others, and on-the-job experience that I can use on my resume.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "What is your best customer service skill?", "answers": ["In any service industry, the needs of the guests should be paramount. The interviewer is asking this question to get a sense of your priorities and your focus. Think about your customer service skills and what might set you apart from others. Be confident in your abilities as you share.", "\"I have several strong customer service skills, but my best is my ability to listen to the customer. If you don't hear them, then how can you help them? I work hard to put myself in the guest's shoes and try to look at things from their perspective. It helps me be empathetic and solution-driven.\"", "\"I believe that my best ability is the way that I interact with the guests. I try to always have a smile on my face, and some pep in the step as we seek to meet their needs. I believe that customers can spot mediocre customer service from a mile away. My job as a hotel manager is to make sure that never happens.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "The hotel manager is responsible for hiring and firing decisions. Share with me any experience you have in this area.", "answers": ["The Hotel Manager will be responsible for hiring decisions so that he can build the best team possible. The interviewer needs to know that you have experience in team-building and employment practices.", "\"I have had extensive experience in the human resources department and believe that I am capable of hiring a quality team. I am not afraid to discipline or even fire someone who is not performing well. Our guests pay too much money for their hotel experience for us to waste our time tolerating underperforming employees.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "This position will require you to have a valid drivers license. Are there any issues you have in this area?", "answers": ["Because a hotel manager is the face and mouth of the property, the interviewer must make sure your record is clean. Be forthright and upfront about any issues.", "\"My driving record is clear and I do not have any issues on my license that I am aware of.\"", "\"I have a ticket or two, but nothing more than that. They have not had any effect on my license.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Having great amenities in a hotel room can make a guest's stay even better. What are some provisions you might put in a room to enhance an experience?", "answers": ["Hotels tend to compete in which offers the best amenities. think about the hotels you have stayed at and determine which amenities might mean the most to a traveler. Reassure the hiring manager that you recognize the need for these items.", "\"Certainly fast and reliable wifi is a critical amenity that the hotel must provide. Without it, guests will not stay at your hotel. Also, I love how Doubletree often puts homemade cookies in the room. I think that is a wonderful idea.\"", "\"I believe that having a good selection of cable channels and a good room service department is a must. Guests want to be able to make their requests and have them met. Valet parking is also important and can make the experience from the moment a guest pulls up.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Our Hotel Manager must show a willingness to listen to the customer. Share with me your ability to do so. What are some ways you have learned to listen to a guest?", "answers": ["No hotel chain impresses everyone every time. There are moments when guests are not satisfied no matter how hard the employees work. The interviewer needs to know how you might respond to this situation, ultimately wanting to be confident that you will be the consulate professional even if a guest is rude or has unrealistic expectations. Reassure the hiring manager that you want to receive feedback and that you take it seriously.", "\"I go over our online reviews every morning so that I can correct any issues that guests might have had. I contact them directly so that I can apologize if needed and offer some kind of perk to keep them as our customers. When guests are in front of me, I never interrupt, but allow them to vent completely about their issue. I have found that most guests just want to be heard, not confronted.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "What do you like the most about the hotel industry?", "answers": ["A hotel manager needs to be a person committed to the idea of hospitality. The interviewer needs to know that the applicant is passionate about providing services to guests and committed to making them happy. Share with the hiring manager how you got started in the hotel business and what about it made you choose it as a career. this is a great opportunity for you to share some of the passion that drives you each day.", "\"I think what I like most is the daily interaction I have with both the staff and our guests. I love to be a positive influence on their days and I know that helping them whether in business or on a pleasure trip is a big part of our responsibility.\"", "\"I love providing a service for a customer and then having the guest appreciate it. Whether that is a room or a well-prepared meal by our chef, or even security for a wedding. I love watching it all unfold. We are in many ways in the memory business.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "How would you handle a situation where the hotel was overbooked and a guest had to be walked?", "answers": ["There are going to be times as a hotel manager where the property is completely sold out or oversold. At times such as these, the guest has to be transferred to another hotel should a room be found for them. The interviewer wants to assess your ability to diffuse a difficult situation. Reassure the hiring manager that you are able to handle tough circumstances.", "\"I would find them another room at a different hotel and pay for it. Then I would attempt to contact the customer personally to inform them of what had happened and reassure them that we have them set up in a nearby property. Then I would offer to pay for a ride to that hotel should they need it.\"", "\"I would personally meet the guest at the front desk to inform them of the situation and offer to find them a room at another property. Then I would pay for that room and offer the shuttle to take them there. I would apologize for the inconvenience but as calmly as I could try to explain the situation and what happened.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Can you handle employee training responsibilities?", "answers": ["Building a quality staff to work in a hotel is not just about hiring the right people, it also means that the staff has to be well-trained. The activity of training requires the attention of the hotel manager. The interviewer needs to know what experience you have had in this regard because it will be crucial to your success. Think about training experience you have led or managed and how you may have overseen the effort.", "\"I believe that each person in your team should know exactly what is expected of them. Then you must demonstrate not just what to do, but how to do it. Training classes are held weekly in the place where I work, and I believe in review and repeat so that our employees never forget.\"", "\"Training employees to go above and beyond what is expected is a priority for me, and I would make it a core pillar of my management.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "We are in the process of setting up second interviews. Is there a time that works best for you?", "answers": ["Congratulations. If the interviewer is asking about a second interview, then it means you have made it past the first round. Be flexible with your schedule. Show enthusiasm that the hiring process is moving forward.", "\"I would also be interested in scheduling another interview. I am available any day of the week other than Thursday.\"", "\"I am available any time you wish. What day works best for you?\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Part of the responsibility for a hotel manager is management of cost controls. Share with me a time when you impacted the bottom line of your company.", "answers": ["Cost control management is an important part of being a hotel manager. The interviewer needs you to understand that containing costs will be a necessary part of the job. Think about a time when you were involved in the process of controlling expenditure control. Be confident in your skillset and attention to detail.", "\"In my previous job, we worked at finding a purveyor for toiletries that allowed us to reduce our expenses by about 14%. I was happy to have worked with the head of their company to negotiate the best deal we could.\"", "\"Our company was having trouble with several of our purveyors raising prices for items in our kitchen. We joined with another property in our chain to negotiate a large contract, and we lowered our costs.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "This position will require you to work nights and weekends. What is your availability in doing so?", "answers": ["The needs of the guest are not 9-5, but 24/7. This means that a hotel manager may need to work odd and long hours.  The interviewer needs to know that you are willing to put in the number of hours that may be needed, covering for absent workers or just supervising others. Reassure the interviewer that you are able to work whenever is needed, even if it means weekends or after midnight.", "\"I am used to working all the time. The job I have now makes me cover for any employee that does not show up. So some days I am in housekeeping and others I am at the front desk. I will have no problem working whenever I need to.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Safety is an important issue for not just guests, but employees. What might you do if you encountered an unsafe condition in the hotel?", "answers": ["Once again, the interviewer is giving you a hypothetical situation and asking you to solve the issue. This type of question is designed to give a realistic appraisal of your ability to observe and correct. Reassure the hiring manager that unsafe conditions should never be tolerated or ignored. The safety of the staff dictates that they be corrected immediately.", "\"I believe in safety both for guests and employees. If I encountered an unsafe condition, I would work hard to correct it. I would have an employee close by clean up the spill or move the housekeeping cart that was blocking the stairs. If no employee was present, I would correct it myself.\"", "\"Safety is paramount. A good manager recognizes these situations and works to correct them. I believe that you have to set an example. If you tolerate an unsafe condition so will your staff, and that just leads to someone getting hurt.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "What kind of benefits package do you need?", "answers": ["Talking about benefits such as health insurance or 401k plans can be important parts of an interview. If the hiring manager is asking this question, then he is attempting to open the door for a frank conversation about what you may need. Use this time to gather information and support the decision you are trying to make.", "\"The hotel chain I work for now offers a complete package of medical, dental, vision, and retirement savings plans. They also offer life insurance and short-term disability. I would be interested in finding out more information about what your company offers.\"", "\"I am glad that you asked that question because one of the factors helping us decide to make a change in career is the benefits we would receive. I have to make sure that my family has adequate coverage. Please tell me what your company has to offer if you don't mind.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "At this hotel chain, we tend to promote from within the company. What is the next progression you would like to see in your hotel career?", "answers": ["The interviewer knows that a promise of advancement could be a primary motivator for you to pursue a career with them. Reassure the hiring manager that you are very interested in continuing your career path with this company, and will work hard to do so.", "\"I'm interested in having a long career with XYZ company. What are the next levels beyond hotel manager? I would welcome any opportunity to advance.\"", "\"I hope to have an opportunity to advance in the near future, perhaps to Regional manager.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "This position requires a background check and drug screen. Are there any issues that we need to know about it.", "answers": ["The hotel company is going to run references, do a background check, and drug screen. The interviewer needs to make sure that there are no skeletons in the closet that have not emerged during the interview. Be forthright about any issues that you have. It may cost you the chance at a job, but the hiring manager will appreciate your not wasting their time.", "\"There are no issues that I am aware of. My background check should pass with flying colors and I do not use drugs.\"", "\"There are no issues that I am aware of. I will be happy to submit to any test your company needs to do.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Have you ever been in an emergency situation that required a life or death decision?", "answers": ["As a hotel manager, there is always the possibility you will be faced with some sort of emergency situation; fire, flood, robbery, etc. The interviewer needs to know that you have the capability of handling these kinds of situations with a calm demeanor. If you panic during a fire, your staff, and guests' safety will be at risk. Think about a time when you had to make decisions that were life and death situations. Be confident in your ability to handle these pressures.", "\"At the property I manage, we had a fire in the kitchen one night. I ran to the back of the restaurant just in time to see the grill go up in flames. We evacuated the hotel and the restaurant called the local fire department and made sure that everyone was all right. I felt like a traffic cop that night, but by clearly giving instructions, we made it through with a minimum amount of hassle.\"", "\"One night a gust had a heart attack in the restaurant I managed. We called the paramedics - reassured the rest of our patrons and worked hard to allow the first-responders to do what they needed to. It was a hard night for all of us, but I thought that staff handled it well.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Each day in your position as a hotel manager, you will receive reports on performance. What is the best indicator if a hotel is doing well?", "answers": ["A good hotel runs good numbers. The interviewer needs to know that you have had experience with these kinds of reports and whether you will be able to identify your performance. Reassure the hiring manager that you recognize the need for statistics and that you know how to grade your hotel's performance so that you can correct any issues.", "\"I believe in a high occupancy rate and a good avg rate per room. These are the two statistics that will tell you how a hotel is doing. A high occupancy rate with a high avg room rate means a lot more profit for the hotel. A low occupancy rate or a low room rate spells trouble. Both have to be maintained effectively.\"", "\"The numbers do not lie. You have to strive to find the sweet spot between the occupancy rate and what you charge for the average room. There is a line there that maximizes profit for the hotel. I also believe that CSI numbers are important. A hotel can fold up very easily with negative reviews, so we should all do as much as we can to keep those positive reviews coming in.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "What was your first position in the hotel industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer is attempting to get a bit of background here. Think about your first job in the hotel business and elaborate on it. Think of this as an opportunity for you to brag on your abilities a bit, and share how you rose into management. Be passionate about your skillset and what your rise in career status has taught you.", "\"I started as a front desk clerk and then worked my way into management, first as an assistant Front desk manager, and eventually to assistant general manager. I have learned so much over the years, but I guess it all comes down to seeing a satisfied guest.\"", "\"I started out in the reservations department answering calls. Then I worked up to the front desk, and housekeeping department and then to the director of sales. In truth, I have done a little bit of everything in the hotel business. I have always prided myself in wanting to learn new skills, and I believe that a good general manager of a hotel should know each department so that when needed they can jump in and help.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The salary packages for Hotel Managers are as varied as the number of hotel chains. Having a salary conversation about compensation can be difficult at best, but it is a necessary one to have. The interviewer is asking this question as an open door for you to ask about compensation and what you need. Consider this an opportunity for you to ask questions and gather information.", "\"I am open to discussing the pay structure offered by Hotel ABC. I have earned a base salary plus commission for the past five years, and I appreciate the security and earnings flexibility that comes with this pay structure. Could you share with me how the company structures pay for its Hotel Managers?\"", "\"I am currently making $128,000 per year with an annual bonus opportunity based on hotel profits and the cost savings that I produce. I am looking for a compensation plan aligned with other hotel management roles in the area and one that provides an opportunity for growth. I look forward to discussing the details of this role so that we can determine a fair compensation plan.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "How would you handle a noisy hotel guest?", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your ability to handle a crisis situation by giving you a hypothetical question to answer. Think about what you might do to prevent a noisy hotel guest from disrupting someone else's night's rest. Reassure the hiring manager that you have the capacity to deal with discrepancies while maintaining your professionalism.", "\"First, I would ask security to call the room to ensure the guest was safe and that an altercation was not occurring. If the phone call did not improve the situation, I would instruct security to go to the room and ask the guests to calm down. If the complaints kept coming, then I the next step would be to ask the guest to remove themselves from the premise. If that request were to be ignored, the next step is to call to police.\"", "\"Part of being a good hotel manager is having the ability to handle problematic behavior. Our security team would ask the guests to quiet down. If there were no improvements in the disturbances, we would ask them to leave or phone the authorities to have them removed depending on how severe the situation was.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "A hotel manager has to know how to lead others. Describe your leadership philosophy for me.", "answers": ["Being an effective hotel manager means that you must lead others to provide guests with the best experience possible. The interviewer needs to know that you have the ability to lead and manage employees well. Reassure the hiring manager of your leadership philosophy by elaborating on a couple of key components. Be confident as your share. This is your opportunity to shine.", "\"I believe that a hotel manager is just that: managing a hotel and its staff. I believe in coaching my employees to excellence just as if I were doing their position myself. A hotel manager cannot do everything, so that means tasks have to be delegated and then supervised. I try to be patient with employees and treat each person as I would want to be treated.\"", "\"I tend to empower employees to do their very best. I think that a big role of a hotel manager is to inspect and demand that employees provide the best experience we can. I don't want to offer a good night's sleep, but a great one. I want our customer's to be raving fans so that they will choose our chain again and again.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "This position requires you to work with third party vendors like Expedia. How familiar are you with working with these kinds of entities?", "answers": ["In this day and age, many customers prefer to book their reservations with third-party applications from their smartphones or computers. Applications like Expedia or Hotels.com often negotiate rates with hotels before posting them online. Reassure the hiring manager that you have the capability to monitor these applications in order to ensure that they are being maximized.", "\"In my previous position, I have worked with many third parties to provide discounts, like AAA or AARP. In the last several years, third-party booking sites have grown exponentially, so I have had to learn how to work with them. I have no problem bringing my expertise in these areas to work in your hotel setting.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "What are three qualities you look for in a hotel that will make you say, this is a nice hotel?", "answers": ["The interviewer is giving you an easy question to open the door for you to separate yourself from the pack. Think about some of the great hotel experiences you have had, and what set them apart. Elaborate on them without going into a great amount of detail Be passionate about what you think a good hotel experience is, and how important it is to provide it.", "\"Our customers pay their hard-earned money for a clean and safe and friendly environment. First, I look for the friendliness of the staff. Are they going out of their way to be helpful and courteous? Second, I want a clean place to stay. Are the public areas clean and free of dust and dirt? Are the rooms cleaned and fresh? Finally, how safe is the place? Is security present? Are their cameras installed? I think that we have a responsibility to ensure that our guests' stay was as pleasant as possible. I want to know that the staff is pleasant and helpful above everything else. If a clerk is rude, that can sour the whole experience. I also look for the cleanliness of the facility, because nothing turns my stomach more than walking over someone else's trash or pulling back clean sheets to see a stain. Finally, I want the building to be in order, with no cracks in the walls, or paint peeling. Anything like that shows that the management staff just does not care.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Our hotel facility includes an extensive food and beverage outlet, what experience do you have in these areas?", "answers": ["Many hotels have restaurants, bars, or banquet facilities attached. Part of the responsibility you may have is managing the staff in charge of those entities. The interviewer needs to know that you have the expertise to handle these varied outlets.\nReassure the hiring manager that you have the ability to multitask.", "\"In my current position I have supervised chefs, restaurant managers, and catering staffs. While our facility is not as large as yours, I don't believe that I will have any trouble working with them.\"", "\"I have managed a large catering complex for years that seats over 1000. Oftentimes, this involved sales of food and beverage. I believe that I have the skills to handle any kind of situation that might arise at this facility.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "There may be a time when the hotel manager will need to represent the hotel to the public. Tell us about your public relations experience.", "answers": ["A hotel manager is the face of the hotel to the public and is responsible for presenting the best possible image to the community. The interviewer needs to know that you will not avoid opportunities to promote the hotel or seek our business opportunities. Discuss your ability to network and publicize your property.", "\"In my previous position, I approved all media packages and determined when and how often we would advertise. In addition, I was a member of the Chamber, and several local service clubs, like Optimist and Rotary. I believe in getting out into the community to promote the hotel as much as possible.\"", "\"I believe that promoting the hotel is vital to the occupancy rate. I would take advantage of every opportunity to keep our presence in front of the consumer. In addition, we would use as many third-party providers as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Describe for me your ability to multitask.", "answers": ["A hotel manager must be an effective multitasker because there is a great deal of stuff to manage. The interviewer needs to know that you can handle the myriad of responsibilities you will face.  Reassure the hiring manager that you have the capability to handle multiple stressors.", "\"I love structure, but have had to teach myself how to multitask and delegate. I try to make a list each morning of what is vital and important so that I can maximize my ability to get tasks done.\"", "\"I live and die by a day planner. This allows me to concentrate on completing tasks.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Building management is an important contributor to the bottom line -share with me your experience here.", "answers": ["One of the largest expenses a hotel manager has to control its energy costs and utilities. The interviewer needs to know that you will be conscious of the various ways to control these expenses. Reassure the hiring manager that you are aware of these costs and how they affect the bottom line. Be confident in your ability to make energy management a priority.", "\"I dislike seeing the lights left on in the offices after the employees are gone. I often walk the property a couple of times a day, turning off lights that do not need to be on, turning off faucets all the way, and adjusting A/C units. These actions seem small but they save a lot of money over the year.\"", "\"I believe in energy management and training our staff to be able to make decisions regarding this. I think that we all need to work on keeping costs down whatever they might be.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "The hotel works with a POS system to process payments. Share with me your experience in this area.", "answers": ["The hotel must work with a POS system to process credit cards and cash payments. The interviewer needs to know that you are familiar with these payment processing utilities.", "\"I have extensive experience with our POS system which may not be exactly the one your hotel uses, but I am sure it is similar. I should have no problems adapting.\"", "\"I have used several POS systems and should have no trouble.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Every hotel guest has a right to privacy. What steps might you take to ensure they have privacy?", "answers": ["The hotel manager handles private information all the time. Think about some ways that you might be able to protect the public display of information to protect and service the guest's interests. Be confident as you share a couple of examples.", "\"I train my staff to never announce a room number over the desk, but instead to write it down and present it to the customer. I'm also careful with ID of any kind.\"", "\"We have to train all staff to recognize the trust that every customer has with them. This will go a long way toward helping protect the information that a customer provides to us.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "A hotel manager must have an attention for detail. How do you keep focused?", "answers": ["A big part of a hotel manager's responsibility is to walk around the property and observe. This requires an attention to detail that exceeds the employees. The interviewer needs to know that you realize that this kind of management must happen. Be confident in your ability to observe and adhere to policies.", "\"I am not the kind of manager who will be stuck in his office all day. I like to be out and about walking the property, observing the interactions that the staff have with guests, even meeting guests themselves. I am not afraid to correct an employee if I need to.\"", "\"A lot of what a good manager does is observe and correct. You have to be willing to get out and see exactly what your employees are doing. If they are adhering to the company policy, great. if not, then they need to rectify the situation immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "How often do you travel? What have some of the experiences with hotel you have stayed at been like?", "answers": ["Every hotel chain has its own set of policies and procedures, but the interviewer wants to know how much experience you have actually had, not just what may be printed on a resume. This question is designed to get you to talk about some of the experiences you have had from a guest's perspective. Reassure the hiring manager that you know what it is like to travel and be on the receiving end of someone else's customer service skills.", "\"I travel constantly and am always on the lookout for how other hotel chains treat their guests. Some of the best experiences I have had I have tried to incorporate into our hotel. The worst, I have notified their corporate office so that the company can take steps to improve their customer service. I feel that they cannot correct a problem they do not know about.\"", "\"I love to travel and have had some great experiences being a guest in someone else's facility. I try to absorb as much as I can so that I can take that experience and bring it home to our hotel. It keeps me on my toes to see how other companies are treating their guests.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "The position of hotel manager requires a knowledge of both front and back of the house. Share with me your exposure to both areas?", "answers": ["A good manager will have experience in both the front and back of the house. Share with the hiring manager your knowledge of each part of the business needs to function to ensure a quality stay for the guests, and how they need to work in tandem to achieve this goal.", "\"I started out in the front of the house working my way up from the front desk. As an assistant general manager, my boss made me work for four weeks in every department, housekeeping, kitchen, dining room, maintenance, and banquets so that I could learn what goes on in the back of the house. It taught me a lot and allows me to be very flexible in how each department should be run.\"", "\"I started in the kitchen learning from Chef XYZ but decided that I wanted to work in the front of the house as well. I think that the experiences of working both front and back have given me a unique idea of how an operation should be run.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Tell me a few things you know about our hotel.", "answers": ["Regardless of the hotel chain, you may be applying for, it is always a good idea to do some online research. This is an opportunity for you to share with the interviewer any research that you have done. Talk about one or two things that might have impressed you about the hotel or the chain you are applying for.", "\"I love the fact that Hotel XYZ cares about its guests. You can see that this particular hotel seems to exceed in providing wonderful service to its customers. You have so many glowing comments on the internet. I also love that you have locations all around the world, so your reputation extends almost everywhere.\"", "\"I was doing some research on the hotel and noticed that you had a rich history here in the city. The hotel was built in 1878 and has been a part of city XYZ for over 150 years almost. Over the years, it has seen a lot of changes, but I love the fact that some of the features like the huge staircase in the lobby are still here. I love the nostalgia of the place.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Hotel staff tend to reflect the personality of their leader. Tell me about how you lead, and how you set the tone for the employees.", "answers": ["A hotel manager must set the tone for the culture of his property. The interviewer is trying to get a read on your leadership skills in order to determine if you will be a good fit. Talk with the hiring manager about your leadership style and what techniques you use to motivate those under you.", "\"I believe in treating people fairly, but firmly. I want to be compassionate, but I also demand excellence. So I used different techniques with different employees. Some staff you can ask something of, and they will do it. Some have to be told what to do, and made to understand the seriousness of what is being asked.\"", "\"I try to never ask an employee to do something I would not do myself. If you want your staff to clean up trash, you have to be willing to pick up trash yourself. So I do not believe that any job is too menial for a hotel manager to do, even if it means making a bed or two.\""]}, {"topic": "Hotel+Manager", "question": "Part of your responsibility is to prevent loss. What are some areas you might institute to prevent stuff from disappearing.", "answers": ["The interviewer needs to know that you can get a handle on loss prevention to keep employees and guests from stealing.", "\"We charge each guest an incidental charge which we refund if nothing gets taken from the room. Most of the missing or stolen goods are caused by employees, not guests. If a problem arose, I would have all managers check purses and employees' belongings at the end of each shift so that we can make sure that nothing is walking out of the loading dock.\"", "\"I would take appropriate steps to deal with any employee I caught taking something that did not belong to them. I have had to work with the police department to catch employees who were stealing money or materials. I have no trouble charging a guest for a set of towels if the maid discovers they have been taken.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "How would you react if a parent complained about a virtual class?", "answers": ["This question prepares you for a likely circumstance. It is impossible to please everyone, and there will always be pushback. If hired in this role as a Distance Learning Specialist. Your answer should provide insight as to how you view parent input and feedback. Note that 'complained' carries a negative connotation, so you'll want your answer to spin it in a positive and productive way as best as you can to prove your ability to handle this situation.", "\"I would first thank the parent for their concern because it means they care. Then I would ask them to explain their doubts or complaints to see if we couldn't find a solution between us, emphasizing that their child's education is central to our methodologies and curriculums. I would be empathetic because I know departing from traditional learning environments produces a learning curve for all of us who experienced something else, so direct feedback from the home is not only expected, it can be a valuable sign. the parent is involved. I want to work with that.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What components would you check if the audio is not working on a computer?", "answers": ["At some point during your interview as their next Distance Learning Specialist, your interviewer will likely ask some technical questions to get at your ability to quickly resolve technical issues your customers will face. This question certainly does that. Prior to your interview, be sure to research and be prepared to answer any technical questions thrown your way and be able to answer them briefly and to the point.", "\"If a student or teacher were to contact me to help resolve a problem related to the audio output on their computer, the first thing I would check is whether the volume had been turned off.  Once I confirm this, I would then go through a series of questions about whether the speakers were connected, if there is power to the audio components, and other connectivity issues.  Finally, I would step the user through several different tests to determine where the problem is and how to resolve it.  The final solution may require a recommendation to replace some of the audio components.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "How will you instruct students with varying abilities?", "answers": ["As their next Distance Learning Specialist, your interviewer needs you to be cognizant of scaffolding material to meet learners where they are at and, at the same time, challenge those who need an extra push. A  virtual classroom of students is full of varying abilities, and you will be responsible for meeting the present needs, whether that means supporting struggling learners or challenging more adept learners. Talk about strategies and methods that you might employ for the range of abilities in your students.", "\"You're always going to have students of varying abilities, whether that is in-person or in a virtual setting. Everyone has strengths and weaknesses, and I know I need to be prepared to help struggling students while also challenging students who catch on quickly to new skills and information. I often mix ability levels when I put students into groups so they can learn from each other. Sometimes, I form groups of similar abilities to check in with students who require more support, and more advanced students can move on to challenge activities together. Other times, I break the class into two groups and instruct each group separately, depending on their needs. Sometimes that means reteaching yesterday's lesson with one group while moving on to more complex or new information with the other group. I also utilize independent work time to check in with individual students. A mixture of all of these techniques helps me target specific groups of students and give everyone what they need.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What would your communication style be with the students you would be working with? How about with the teaching staff?", "answers": ["The interviewer is trying to gauge your communication with this question, and how you interface with both students and colleagues. Whatever your communication style may be, be sure to describe it in a concise manner that will resound positively with the interviewer. Keep in mind that your communication style can certainly vary a bit when talking about communicating with students and teachers. If you personally would take different approaches with each, feel free to discuss your approaches with your interviewer.", "\"With the students that I would be working with, my approach would of course depend on their age level. But no matter their age, I would communicate them in a friendly and direct manner, encouraging them as they navigate their career as a virtual student. In regards to the teachers and educators on the team, I would be professional, honest and direct. I know that my expertise is valuable, so if I want to have the ears and the respect of students and colleagues alike, then I model the same in the way I communicate with them.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "As our next Distance Learning Specialist, what values and traits would you bring to our team that would help promote teamwork and collaboration?", "answers": ["In both the traditional and virtual school settings, the entire staff must collaborate to provide the best possible educational outcomes for the entire student body. In this role as a Distance Learning Specialist, you will cooperate on a regular basis with teachers, administrators, and curriculum developers. Your interviewer wants to know that you can collaborate effectively with any staff member at their organization, so talk about how you facilitate cooperation. Lastly, try to explain why a true team effort is so important to the success of students.", "\"Throughout my career, I've always been commended for being the ultimate team player. It begins with clear communication, including listening. I value what my team wants to bring to the table, and I encourage them to brainstorm. I also rely on my ability to read people, and I try to respond appropriately. I also know my limitations. We were all educated and trained in our niche areas. I know I can't be everything to my students nor do I try, so I never hesitate to enlist the help of a counselor, aide, principal, or curriculum developer when their expertise is needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "As a Distance Learning Specialist, do you believe you should build rapport with students and their families?  If yes, how?", "answers": ["Building relationships with students and their families will be a key aspect in the role of a Distance Learning Specialist. Students must like you, respect you and feel like they belong to feel fully invested in their virtual education. Rapport is an important aspect of influencing others. Explain how you build rapport with students and end your response with how this benefits both students and their families. You may want to consider building classroom culture, trust, or a sense of belonging amongst students.", "\"Absolutely, rapport is essential. Students respond positively when they feel like the teacher cares and has a genuine connection with them. The same is true for a Distance Learning Specialist too. I build rapport by getting to know the people in their lives during one-on-one talks. As well, I also build rapport and trust by following through on my word and by listening and responding to student and colleague alike. My word is only as good as the actions that reinforce them, and so I make a point of following through on my commitments to the best of my ability.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Innovation in distance learning is evolving as rapidly as the technology to support it. In what way do you think distance learning will change next?", "answers": ["As more and more students and families and schools move to include virtual learning as part of their daily routine, new innovation will continue to develop to make the virtual learning world more normative. Your interviewer will want to hear that you have an open eye for how the technology will innovate in the coming years. The interviewer should have a clear impression that you are ready to handle any new innovations that come to the distance learning field, and have a sense to anticipate a truly innovative project versus just a passing one.", "\"Tools and technology in distance learning have progressed rapidly in recent years. I expect none of that to slow down. I'm aware of a growing movement to include virtual reality in the virtual classroom. As video game developers are perfecting VR, there will be many other uses for it too. Imagine taking a group of high school history students back to ancient Rome through virtual reality.  While I am definitely not an expert on it, I also have a strong feeling that artificial intelligence will completely change the way virtual students learn and virtual teachers educate in the future. From an educator's perspective, AI will likely manage administrative burdens so that educators can better focus on their students. And for the student, AI will be able to customize learning. The future possibilities are endless.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Are you fluent and adaptable when it comes to learning new computer programs and software?", "answers": ["As you are aware, the education field has become much more technologically-driven and this rings especially true for both students and educators in a distance learning environment. If hired to be their next Distance Learning Specialist, you will likely use a variety of new systems and programs and your interviewer wants to ensure that you will be able to learn and master these quickly. Adding another tricky piece to this puzzle, many school districts have their own customized email programs and websites in which you will need to be effective and efficient. As you answer this question, reiterate that you have excellent computer skills and don't hesitate to give examples of the variety of programs that you have worked in throughout your career.", "\"I am computer literate and am confident in my ability to learn any program required for this role. In my current role, I work in the entire Microsoft Office suite and have a lot of knowledge and skills with word processing and Excel spreadsheets. I also have experience working with a few different email systems. In my current role, I also upload information on my organization's Facebook, Instagram and Twitter pages so parents are aware of new curriculum.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "We need our Distance Learning Specialist to have strong written communication skills. How would you rate your written communication skills?", "answers": ["Your interviewer is getting a good indication of your verbal communication skills during your interview process. But because written communication skills are so important in the success of a Distance Learning Specialist, your interviewer is posing this question to you to get an idea of your strengths as a writer. As you rate your written communication skills, be sure to talk about your written projects from previous roles. Don't hesitate to talk about formal curriculum instructions or learning content that you have authored.  Even discussing clear and consistent communication in email and memos is important in this role as well, so talk about why taking the time to write clearly is important in your work. However you answer, make sure that your interviewer walks away knowing that written communications are essential to your career.", "\"My written communication skills are strong. As you can see in the portfolio I've provided, the written lessons that I developed are clear, concise and error-free. Any time that I write, I take time to proofread and even use a program like Grammarly to ensure that both grammar and spelling mistakes are avoided. I take this same approach when I draft other communications like internal memos and emails as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What technical problem-solving tools do you feel are mandatory for your work as a Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["As you prepare to answer a question like this, be prepared to talk about the tools and resources that you would use to solve issues with video conferencing and online learning apps. If needed, be sure to research those types of systems so that your knowledge is fresh.", "\"Having had a lot of hands-on experience with Blackboard, I foresee that as being the largest area for troubleshooting in this role. If I couldn't suss out the problem on my own strengths, I know the app has a great troubleshooting site that I have used plenty of times and could refer to if needed. As well, I would have their help desk on speed dial for the times I needed them. Regarding the videoconferencing tools that your team uses with students, I have experience with Zoom and Microsoft, and I'm confident in my ability to help users get connected via video and audio and how to walk them through all functions of those programs. When more advanced support would be needed in any similar system, I would research all backside functions of that system. The same would be true if I were accepted as your new Distance Learning Specialist.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What process would you use when troubleshooting remote IT issues that students or teachers were having?", "answers": ["As a competent and successful Distance Learning Specialist in this role, you will need to have a firm grasp on troubleshooting all aspects of the systems you the students and staff use.  As you interview for this role, it is important to understand that IT support is 80% technical knowledge and 20% speculation. You first have to have a fundamental understanding of information technology and how the systems and programs work. In addition, you need to act as a detective to find the cause of an issue in order to resolve it. The process you describe should incorporate both of these elements. It should also be consistent so that any technical issue can be resolved quickly and efficiently. As you answer, make sure to talk about your knowledge and experience with the systems you would be working with, in this role.", "\"I would first listen to the user in order to diagnose the issue, and then I would move onto resolving the issue for them. If I needed to research a proper fix, I would make that a top priority to ensure that learning isn't hindered. From a technical perspective, I'm proficient as a trouble-shooter with virtual learning programs like Blackboard and Seesaw, as I have a lot of experience in these systems. And I'm sure I could learn similar systems too. I also have a lot of experience in virtual meeting spaces like Zoom and Skype to be able to assist both students and teachers with needs within those systems.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Talk about your ability to be flexible on the job. Why do you think it is important to be flexible in this role as our next Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["In looking to hire the next Distance Learning Specialist on their team, your interviewer needs the ideal candidate to be flexible and adaptive. In this role, there are many factors and duties that will require you to be flexible. Whether it is working with and supporting a diverse team of educators, each with their own needs, or jumping to and from the many different duties required for this role, your interviewer wants to hear that you can handle the twists and turns of the work. Answer with an example, and talk about why flexibility and adaptability are critical skills for this role.", "\"I consider myself a flexible person on the job. I enjoy dynamic work environments that require thinking on my feet, problem-solving, and collaborating with others. When I have to troubleshoot in my current job, I know that new information might mean I have to change course, or reveal to me an issue that must then go back through my colleagues so they can be prepared. And helping my team is one of the aspects of my work I value most. And sometimes that means we have to chase the rabbit trails in order to find solutions.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "How would you bring a sense of energy and positivity as our Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["While no one can be both of these things all of the time, your interviewer is looking to hire a Distance Learning Specialist that can make a difference in the daily lives of students who may be struggling in the virtual environment. What are your strategies for being intentional about these virtues?", "\"Yes, I'm a very positive person, and the work itself provides me a lot of energy. But I still need to motivate myself. So I make a point of connecting in some way to a colleague or student. It doesn't have to be much, but something that reminds me to truly see the people around me. This may not seem like much, but it helps me show up every day with positive energy for the people that I am serving.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "As our next Distance Learning Specialist, how would you help to engage parents in their child's learning?", "answers": ["Keeping parents engaged and involved in their child's learning is one of the dilemmas schools and teachers often face. This issue can be compounded even more so in the virtual learning environment. By asking this question, your interviewer is looking for a candidate that recognizes the value of parental involvement and has innovative ways of making that happen. Prior to your interview, try to think of a creative way or two that you could help encourage parents to be involved in the coursework you would be creating in this role.", "\"I have found that a lack of tools or awareness often impede parents from engaging with their child's learning in the virtual environment. I am a firm believer in providing parents with written instructions on all of the technological tools that their child will be required to know and understand. Since they are physically in the home, there usually comes a time when they have to help troubleshoot a quick issue and this is especially true with younger children. I am also a firm believer that learning programs need to be designed with parental involvement in mind. When learning from home, some students will be completing work in the evening time while others complete it during the morning hours due to family circumstances. Curriculum needs to allow the family's to adjust to what works for them, and involving parents is vital in this process.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "If hired as our next Distance Learning Specialist, how would you handle the job-related stress that comes with the position?", "answers": ["Because this role will put you working with a large group of educators and students, there will be times where you may be pulled in several directions on the job and this can cause a great deal of stress for any person. In asking this question, your interviewer is ideally looking to hear that you can stay calm, cool and collected when faced with stress on the job. As you answer, talk about your ability to prioritize work and take your tasks one at a time to ensure that you are giving every task its full attention.  As well, be sure to talk about ways that you stay organized in your work and don't hesitate to give an example of a time where you had to work under a great deal of pressure.", "\"I handle stress well on the job and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand, doing my best to keep from being distracted.. This means that when engrossed with a task, I stay away from email until the work is complete. Staying on deadline is helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "You have been hired as the newest member of our team. How would you first introduce yourself to a group of parents, students, and teachers from our school?", "answers": ["If your interviewer asks an open-ended question like this during your interview, it can be difficult to know where to begin...and end! This question haunts many individuals who may accidentally go a little too in-depth into their personal lives. It happens. Keep your reply light, and relevant to the job. Share how you became interested in this career path and what you enjoy about it. This is a great opportunity to describe yourself by discussing the strengths and qualities that you bring to the overall educational experience as the Distance Learning Specialist.", "\"I am a nurturing individual and like to mentor those that I work with, in unique ways. And I'm driven. I would introduce myself as a subject matter expert on all things in the virtual learning environment, from using simple video conferencing apps to authoring virtual learning modules for students. I would let everyone know that my goal is to be a resource for them in their virtual learning journey and that I always have a virtual open-door policy for them to reach out to me at any time.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "When observing the effectiveness of a distance learning program, what factors do you consider for evaluation?", "answers": ["The observation and evaluation of virtual learning lessons and programs has certainly brought a number of new challenges to educators when compared to the traditional in-person classroom setting. In asking this question, your interviewer is looking to hear that you understand what these challenges are in the distance learning world, and that you are prepared to evaluate programs effectively as their next Distance Learning Specialist. Prior to your interview, be sure to think about the challenges of virtual distance learning, and be able to address how you would evaluate the key facets.", "\"I have experienced this over the last two years when my own classroom went virtual. For one, I know it's critical to establish criteria for the students so they are clear on what they must know from one lesson to the next. I achieve this in a number of ways. Sometimes through direct interaction with the students. Sometimes I do so via written assignments or tests. Another key to evaluating the effectiveness is accessibility. In a classroom setting, student accessibility was less of a concern because students were literally present in the classroom. In the virtual world of education, I need to take into account the accessibility of mixed media like presentations and videos and audio lectures, as well as platforms and even connectivity. It's critical for all students to have access. Poor access has a direct impact on the quality of education.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "As we are considering you as our next Distance Learning Specialist, what experiences or credentials set you apart from others interviewing for the role?", "answers": ["While your interviewer can tell a lot about your education, experience and credentials by looking at your resume, they want you to walk them through your path that led you to this interview. As you answer, be sure to highlight the experiences and education that truly makes you a unique and well-qualified candidate to be their next Distance Learning Specialist.", "\"As you can see from my resume, I taught at two different elementary grade levels for seven years before pursuing my Master's degree. During my years in the classroom, I developed a strong passion for developing impactful lessons and decided to take this next step in my career to pursue the virtual learning environment.  I am currently licensed to teach in Florida, Georgia and South Carolina as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Do you have any prior video editing experience that you can bring to this role as our next Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["As their next Distance Learning Specialist, you may be asked to edit and upload videos to the online learning system so that students have access to updated and innovative videos. Your interviewer is looking to get a feel for what type of experience you have in video editing and uploading and how that experience will apply to this role. If you don't have a lot of experience in formally editing videos, there is no need to fret as this will be a skill that can be learned on the job. Just make sure you do as much research as possible on what video editing tools you can talk about. If you do have experience in video editing and uploading, that is great! Be sure to talk about that experience and the level of your proficiency.", "\"Yes, I do have experience in working with educational videos within the Blackboard system. I have uploaded video files and associated dialogue on much of the coursework I've created in the system and am very comfortable in handling this task. I've also created and edited videos using the Windows Moving Maker and iMovie programs.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What experience have you had with students from culturally diverse backgrounds?", "answers": ["As a Distance Learning Specialist in this role, you will have the opportunity to work with students and families that come from different backgrounds and your interview will be looking to hear that you will be able to do this effectively. If you have had direct experience with students from culturally diverse backgrounds, talk about an example that displays your cultural sensitivity. You may want to use a story that highlights how you could adapt to the student's particular needs. If you haven't had any direct experience working with people from a diverse range of cultures, you can give the interviewer confidence by mentioning examples of your ability to be fair and consistent and sensitive. Be ready and willing to share any resources you use to continue to develop as an educator and ensure the content you teach is culturally responsive.", "\"I have completed diversity training, and I try to be fair and consistent in the way I treat everyone. Regardless of anyone's culture or ability, children generally respond to a teacher who listens carefully and adapts to their specific needs. I treat everyone as a unique individual and want everyone to feel as if they belong. I also love to include and celebrate different cultures, languages, and abilities in the children that I work with. In this role, I am cognizant of the fact that each student and their family will have different levels of knowledge on the technology they will be using as distance learners, and to the best of my ability I will take all cultural differences in the experience with the systems to mind when working with individuals.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What challenges are you looking for in a position as a Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["State your current experience and contrast it with the challenge you're looking for in seeking this position. Explain why you want this challenge, and how it'll help you in your career, and what its place is in your trajectory. Describe why challenges are appealing to you and what role you might play in finding solutions. The interviewer does not want to hire someone who will complain about problems they face at work; they're looking for a motivated person who is willing to ask the tough questions and do the work to find solutions that improve the school. Be sure to demonstrate an ambitious attitude and a willingness to do your part.", "\"As an experienced educator who's always thrived in the technological aspects of the classroom setting, I'm looking forward to the challenges of becoming a Distance Learning Specialist. I think that virtual and online schooling will be a hot topic in the future with more and more families and students looking to make that change. I'm confident in my ability to learn, grow and thrive into the future of this role and look forward to doing it with your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What do you like to do in your spare time?", "answers": ["It's important for the interviewer to know they are considering a well-rounded individual as their next Distance Learning Specialist. They also want to gauge your personality and interests for sake of team compatibility. So share a few activities you genuinely enjoy. It is also important for leadership to see that you have ways of recharging yourself so that you can invest in your students.", "\"I really enjoy going to the movies, hiking, trying new restaurants, and spending time with my family and friends. I crave daily physical activity, so I do my best to stay active by running and biking, which also helps manage my stress so I can have the energy to keep up with my students!\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What qualities do you believe make an excellent Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["As you prepare for your interview as a Distance Learning Specialist, consider the qualities that your interviewer will be looking for in the ideal candidate for this role.  By reading the job description and doing some research on the organization you will be interviewing with, you'll be able to decipher these key qualities. You might want to emphasize your adaptability and your innovativeness. No matter how you answer this question, affirm that you will be the right person to bring these qualities to this role.", "\"In my experience, a Distance Learning Specialist needs to combine both the worlds of a frontline educator and a technical expert. Excellent computer skills and technical troubleshooting ability are essential skills. Over the past two years, I have worked closely with systems like Google Classroom and the Blackboard portal and can work from the administrative side of these systems effectively. I also have a lot of experience in videoconferencing systems like Zoom and Cisco WebEx. But interpersonal skills are also critical in this role. Being an active listener, and communicating clearly whether verbally or written, cannot be undervalued. From my years of experience in the classroom setting, you can feel confident that I have what it takes to communicate effectively with both teachers and students in this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What would you find to be most rewarding in this role as our next Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["Your interviewer wants to get a feel for your commitment and your passion for this role. What motivates you? What keeps you coming back? This is the time to let your passion for education really shine through! Prior to your interview, prepare to talk about one or two aspects of this job that you will find the most rewarding, both personally and professionally. As you answer, emphasize your compatibility with this role.", "\"Over the last couple of years, I have witnessed the need for virtual learning become more and more apparent, and I'm excited to be on the forefront of that movement. Learning in a virtual environment--away from face to face contact with both teachers and peers--is difficult for a lot of students. I want to make the virtual learning environment as effective and impactful for both students and teachers. I want to bridge the gap that students may feel, and emphasize the potential for teachers and students alike. Also, the fact that innovation in technology and instructional methods will continue to grow in the years to come makes this role exciting for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What leadership qualities would you bring to our team as our Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["While you likely won't have any direct reports that you supervise in this role as a Distance Learning Specialist, you will be called upon to be a leader when it comes to the design and implementation of distance learning and online learning programs. Since the teaching staff will look to you for leadership and guidance, your interviewer wants to hear that you bring solid leadership skills to their team.  Prior to your interview, be sure to consider your leadership qualities and your experience as a leader in preparation for this question.", "\"I'm a decisive leader. I'm not afraid to make a judgement call. But more importantly, I listen to the ideas brought by the team, and I'm glad to implement them into the final project. And I lean on my expertise on the technological side too, and it allows me a different perspective. In addition, over the last couple of years, I have taken many workshops and courses to build on my leadership skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What would be an initial weakness or hurdle you would have to overcome if hired as our next Distance Learning Specialist?", "answers": ["Your interviewer is looking to hear that you are cognizant of any aspects of the job where you would need to work harder to come up to speed to be fully competent. Given the fact that the Distance Learning Specialist field is new, your interviewer isn't expecting to hire someone that can come in and have every aspect of the job mastered. Prior to your interviewer, be sure to read the job description thoroughly and be honest with yourself about the largest potential hurdles. As you answer, do your best to turn this initial weakness that you have into a growth opportunity. Show that you are willing to put in the time and effort to become fully capable in this role.", "\"For me, the biggest hurdle will be making the transition from a classroom teacher to this role. With my many years of experience in working with both middle school and high school aged students, it will take a proper mindset for me to step way from the frontline educator role. I would no longer be on the forefront of driving content, rather I'd be working in the role of support on the backend for development and implementation of the online coursework. It's a paradigm shift for sure, but I'm ready to make this career change. I'm passionate about it, and I'm ready to learn and to lead this team.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What does a model virtual classroom look like to you?", "answers": ["In recent years, more and more schools and teachers were beginning to re-think how they structure their traditional classrooms to better align with youth development stages and to maximize the learning potential for all students. With the emergence of the virtual classroom, paradigms have been upended for educators and administrators. Your interviewer is proposing this question to get an idea for how you view the virtual classroom setting, and to see if you have a good idea of what makes the environment a success for students. Prior to your interview, try to do as much research on this role and the organization to give you some insight into the type of setting that they are currently using.", "\"I appreciate the benefits of structure with the freedom of choice that comes with distance learning and this is what honestly drew me to make a change to a Distance Learning Specialist. I like to set up my classrooms so that we may have a central place to come together and learn with mixed desk options to accommodate a variety of learning styles. With students learning from a home environment, incorporating breakout sessions for students of equal ability would be a great advantage and easy to accomplish.  At times I would pair advanced students with struggling students, and the virtual model takes some of the potential stigma out of such an exercise because they are not in full view of the rest of the students. Student engagement is the final piece of my model virtual classroom. In a traditional classroom setting, getting students to engage was pretty easy compared to this new virtual world. With that said, designing lessons and coursework that require engagement in a group setting is very important to the overall student experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "How would you define customer service in this role as a Distance Learning Specialist, and what steps would you take to ensure you are providing exceptional service?", "answers": ["One of the most important roles of a Distance Learning Specialist is customer service. To be able to successfully answer this question, you must first understand that your customers will come in the form of both frontline educators and students.  You shouldn't confuse solving technical issues with helping users get back to doing their jobs using technology.  When interviewing for this role, keep in mind that you are first a customer service representative and second a technologist.  This will also help you when you are doing the job, keeping you focused on a positive customer experience rather than being distracted by an interesting technical problem.", "\"As your next Distance Learning Specialist, I fully understand that my customers would be both students and educators, and the service I provide to each is vital to the success of distance learning programs.  In my opinion, customer service is providing an excellent customer experience for the people with whom I interact. I would provide excellent service by actively listening to what their issue is, then diagnosing their issue and then setting a fair timeline for resolution.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Do you have any experience providing direct training to fellow colleagues or team members?", "answers": ["Part of the role as a Distance Learning Specialist will require you to provide training for teachers learning the online systems and videoconferencing tools they will be using. Your interviewer is looking to hear that you are comfortable and confident in your ability to provide training in both a one-on-one and large group setting. In preparation for this interview, think of a few examples of successful training sessions you've delivered during your career. Your interviewer wants evidence that when you develop and deliver a training session, you focus on accomplishing the company's goals while creating engaging and enjoyable learning opportunities for your attendees. Your interviewer also wants to see your passion for delivering impactful training sessions, and they want evidence that you understand what makes a successful training session.", "\"Yes, I do have experience in providing content training in front of large groups and with individuals. During my career as a teacher, I spent four years as my district's Instructional Specialist and this role came with yearly staff training on implementing effective teaching strategies within the classroom. I've collaborated with principles and the district administrator on creating relevant training content for elementary, middle and high school teachers, and I was entrusted with delivering the content in a town hall setting with teachers at each school.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Distance Learning Specialists should also be avid learners. Talk about a recent professional development effort and how you approached expanding your knowledge.", "answers": ["Because the propensity to move to a more virtual learning environment is so recent for so many schools, the Distance Learning Specialist role is expected to grow and morph into the future as new advancements come about. Your interviewer wants to ensure that you would step into this role willing and ready to keep yourself educated and up to speed on new trends in the evolving field. Talk about a recent professional development opportunity, and how it impacted you. Reiterate to your interviewer why remaining a student is critical to your professional success.", "\"In all honesty, the future growth and adaptation of the virtual learning model is what drew me to this career path. The field is dynamic, and the coming years will reveal new technology and innovation. Over the past year alone, I have earned continuing education credits in family engagement in the classroom, creating LGBTQ+ inclusive schools, and educator wellness initiatives. I'm committed to creating fun and effective learning environments and materials, and I hope to do so as your Distance Learning Specialist.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What would be your favorite approach for motivating the students that you would be supporting in their virtual environment?", "answers": ["As a Distance Learning Specialist in this role, you will spend a great deal of face to face time virtually with students, but there are many potential distractions in this environment too. If asked this question during your interview, your interviewer is looking to hear a creative way or two that you would help motivate and focus the students. While this is an open-ended question with no right or wrong answer, make sure that your interview knows that you will be personally invested in the motivation of your students.", "\"I think that the learn-from-home model is definitely a challenge for any aged student, especially those that had participated in a traditional classroom setting prior to going virtual. A huge part of that challenge is not having the face to face interaction and social time with their peers. To minimize this challenge, I would promote virtual interaction and collaboration among the students to help motivate them as a whole. And positive reinforcement is never a bad strategy either.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Talk about your favorite leader you have had during your career. What qualities did they have that stood out to you the most?", "answers": ["This question hopes to get a glimpse of what you value in a leader, and how you exemplify those values.  Provide an example of a leader who has had a lasting impression on you and influenced your own leadership skills. This question also allows your interview the chance to see what you desire out a leader that supervises your work. Discuss the different qualities your favorite leader has, and how those qualities have impacted the way you work and how that would impact your role in the new organization.", "\"My current district administrator definitely comes to mind. He encourages his entire team to be innovative and open-minded. We are given a lot of room to explore so that we can come up with new ways of solving not only curriculum problems, but also other problems in the district and classrooms. He will conduct brainstorming events with staff to help drive the philosophy that we should be initiators instead of executors. While I make it sound like he's a creative person, he is actually data-driven and analytical. This resonates with me. I've adopted the same philosophy with the educators on my team. I always encourage them to step out of their comfort zone and learn what they can from outside forces. I like to foster an environment in which everyone feels like a leader, and that they have a stake in the outcome.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "If hired as our Distance Learning Specialist, how would you adapt when asked to make last-minute changes to a program?", "answers": ["In this role, there will be times when you will need to make quick changes to virtual instructional materials, and you need to be able to handle these changes with professionalism. Your interviewer is trying to gauge your adaptability under pressure and flexibility in the workplace as their next Distance Learning Specialist. Show the interviewer that you can embrace change. If possible, provide an example of a time when you had to make last-minute changes to the curriculum.", "\"I can take the pressure of last-minute changes,  and I've proven this throughout my career. Last year, I was working with a district's middle and high school sciences department to create online virtual labs for distance learners. After taking their ideas and creating a robust curriculum for all grade levels which included life sciences, chemistry and physics, I was asked to make some last minute changes to the chemistry curriculum. It was Early August, less than a month to the new school year. So I jumped right into the recommended changes that came from the district. I didn't take the changes personally, because I always work closely with the educators and let them have the final say over the curriculum. In order to be finished on time, I stayed in constant email communication with them, and the amended curriculum was finished in time for the new school year.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "Tell me about your experience working with educators as subject matter experts. How do you ensure you can work with them effectively to achieve learning goals?", "answers": ["As a Distance Learning Specialist, you typically won't be expected to be a subject matter expert in all educational areas. However, you will be expected to work harmoniously with frontline educators distilling information about tasks and processes and documenting the information, and then translating it into learning courses and materials. By proposing this question to you, your interviewer wants to learn about your collaborations with educators as subject matter experts. Describe how you achieve success through cooperative efforts.", "\"Over the course of my career, I have worked with a wide variety of educators with great success. In fact, I work to collaborate with them regularly in my current role. I develop the materials and the educators are the experts providing the content. It's important that we build trust together. I aim to be knowledgeable, friendly and honest, and I expect the same in return from them. I deliver on my word and don't hesitate to communicate any feedback I have for them.\""]}, {"topic": "Distance+Learning+Specialist", "question": "What do you consider to be your greatest work-related accomplishment?", "answers": ["With this question, your interviewer wants to gain a sense of your values and drivers because accomplishments can say something about both. They're also looking for concrete evidence of your competency.  A successful answer will highlight your passion for your work and the aspects that give you fulfillment. Be sure to mention any accolade or outcome that directly followed this accomplishment. Assure your interviewer that you continue to set career goals in the field and in this new opportunity too.", "\"There are a couple of work-related accomplishments that come to mind. During my recent annual performance review, my administrator commended me for being so flexible and adaptable over the last year and a half during a pandemic. The teaching staff was under immense pressure when schools went virtual and I had to help lead the way in designing new curriculum that would work for the younger grade levels.  While I'm not a person that needs a pat on the back, it was very humbling to be recognized personally by them.\n\nI've also collected a number of comments that I've received from the educators that I work with on a daily basis. From my first day on the job, they've always appreciated my honesty, knowledge and friendly personality. When at one time many of the staff thought the relationship between teachers and curriculum development was more of a war, I brought  a sense of peace and harmony.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Describe a difficult project and how you overcame it?", "answers": ["As a board chairman, there will be times where you are responsible for handling difficult projects.  The interviewer wants to know how well you handle these situations. Describe a difficult project that you overcame. If you have an example related to the duties outlined in the job description, it is good to use that one. In your response, provide details of the project, the challenges you faced, how you overcame them, and the outcome.  Be sure to share how your efforts resulted in a positive impact.", "\"In my previous role as a non-profit director, I faced a difficult challenge related to our budget.  We were faced with a financial shortage that caused us to evaluate whether or not we would have the resources to fulfill our mission. With the help of my leadership team, we were able to identify areas where we could reduce funding while still operating successfully. The result was minimal impact to our staffing and operations, and we were able to revisit the areas where we cut costs once we received additional funding.\"", "\"As a leader in my organization, I am faced with difficult projects regularly.  I've learned to respond by being patient, getting all of the details, and making sound decisions based on input from my team, and ultimately by keeping the goals of the company in mind first.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Where do you think your strengths fit in with the current board?", "answers": ["Each board member comes with their own strengths. The interviewer wants to know how your strengths will be beneficial to the current board.  It's a good idea to learn about the strengths and weaknesses of a board or organization before your interview.  This tells you their pain points or areas of struggle that they need to improve.  In your response, express how your skills and attributes will impact those areas.", "\"After reading about your organization's history, I understand that one of your pain points has been fundraising.  With my previous experience working for a non-profit, I have a knack for finding unique funding opportunities and a strong community network.  I feel strongly about being able to expand your reach when looking for fundraising opportunities and will continuously monitor our performance.\"", "\"I think being able to lead others towards a common goal is necessary for every board.  I've been successfully doing this in previous positions, and my passion for your mission will drive me to do the same while serving on your board.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What do you feel is the most important thing we do for the community?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how much you know about the organization.  Before your interview, take some time to read the organization's website, reviewers, and other news so you can learn what it is they do.  This will give you an idea of the organization's history, activities, and communities they serve.  Show the interviewer that you've done your research and also be prepared to share what you feel is their most important community effort and why.", "\"After reading stories about your activities in the community, I realize that all of your community efforts have a significant impact, so it is hard to choose one.  However, if I have to choose, I'd say that the most important thing you do for the community is XYZ.  These efforts help improve the lives of others by not only assisting during times of need but by helping them get on the right path for the future.\"", "\"I've witnessed firsthand your impact in the community which is why I would love to join your board.  I am especially impressed with your efforts geared towards increasing the capacity to serve others in underserved communities.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What recruitment methods do you use to attract employees or other board members?", "answers": ["As a board member, recruitment is something you'll do for new employees and other board members.  Part of your job is to be on the lookout for people who can bring their experience and talent to the board.  Share how you will attract the best talent for positions in the organization and on the board.  Some examples include networking, community events, recruiters, job boards, and headhunters.", "\"I believe the best way to recruit for new board members is through networking.  This gives me the opportunity to educate prospective members about our mission, activities and even invite them to attend meetings to get a glimpse of what they could expect as a board member.  This also allows them to see how their skills and experience might benefit our organization.\"", "\"When recruiting for new employees, I like using the new ATS systems that allow you to sort by specific criteria such as location, skills, and education level.  This allows me to narrow down my search and find the candidates that possess the exact qualifications I'm looking for.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Why do you want a career as a board chairman?", "answers": ["Being a board chairman comes with great responsibility but also a great sense of satisfaction. The interviewer would like to know your reason or motivation for wanting to become a boards chairman.  In your response, discuss the impact you'd like to make, your background that has equipped you for this role, your leadership goals, or even your desire to contribute to the organization's mission.  Whatever your reason, make sure your response demonstrates your ability to add value to the organization.", "\"I studied finance in college and have held various roles in finance and management. My goal of becoming a board chairman comes from my desire to positively impact your organization in a leadership role, and more importantly, I want to help make decisions that drive you closer to fulfilling your overall mission.\"", "\"As a board chairman, I know I will strengthen my leadership skills and be exposed to various leadership styles. I am also very passionate about your mission to do XYZ.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How will you stay current on trends and developments that may impact the organization?", "answers": ["Staying on top of trends and developments not only allows you to stay ahead of the competition but also ensures you are offering products and services that meet the current needs of your audience.  It also ensures your organization is using systems and processes that aren't outdated.  Share how you stay current on the latest trends and developments.  Some examples may include reading blogs, subscribing to related news providers, attending conferences, and networking with others.", "\"Every year I attend a national conference in our industry.  At the conference, I get a chance to meet others who are doing the work we do, and I also get to hear about new advances in our industry.  It is one of the best ways to hear about trends on the rise.\"", "\"Staying up to date on trends and developments is very important to me.  I subscribe to newsletters and blogs, so new information is sent right to my email regularly.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Do you consider yourself a leader?", "answers": ["By definition, a leader can lead others, have authority, and make people work together towards a common goal.  The interviewer wants to know if you consider yourself a leader and if you have what it takes to lead people inside and outside of their organization.   Whether or not you have officially held leadership roles, you may possess leadership qualities.  Be honest in your response and share if you possess the following common qualities of a leader:\n\n-Good communicator\n-Has a vision for the future\n-Empathetic\n-Accountable\n-Expresses gratitude", "\"I definitely consider myself a leader.  I currently serve in a leadership role, and every day, my mission is to ensure our workforce is working together towards our company's goals.  In areas that may be weak, I have been committed to identifying ways to perform better, create stronger teams, and stay ahead of the competition.  I will apply this same effort and dedication here in my role as a board chairman.\"", "\"I haven't officially held any leadership roles, but my references will tell you that I possess many qualities of a good leader.  I'm great at motivating others, communicating well, and seeing the big picture for an organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What makes our organization's mission powerful for you?", "answers": ["When selecting members of a board, organizations want people who will be passionate about advancing the mission.  Think about why you've chosen this organization.  Perhaps you are passionate about the impact it makes in the community, or maybe the purpose resonates with you personally.  The interviewer wants to know why you feel their mission is powerful.  Express your thoughts and feelings about the mission.  Be descriptive and honest in your answer.", "\"Your mission to provide educational opportunities to underserved communities is powerful to me because I know firsthand that there is a need.  Your organization opens up doors for others who might not otherwise have access to the services you offer.  Your organization changes the trajectory of so many lives in a positive way.\"", "\"I've read many success stories from people your organization has impacted, so I know your mission is changing our communities for the better.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What are your expectations of other board members?", "answers": ["Every board member brings their own unique set of skills and experience to a board with the overall goal to fulfill the organization's mission.  Share with the interviewer what you will expect from the other board members.", "\"A board is a leadership team.  I will expect the other board members to support each other, professionally represent the organization, have open and honest communication, and work together harmoniously to meet our goals. As a board chairman, I will offer the same to my fellow board members.\"", "\"I expect the other board members to be committed.  Every perspective, effort, and skill set is important, and when one person doesn't do their part, others are impacted.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Do you have experience speaking in front of groups?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know your public speaking skill level.  As a board chairman, you know that speaking in front of people will be a regular part of your duties.  Feel free to bring a previously recorded video or presentation of you speaking in front of a large group if you have one.  Otherwise, be prepared with examples that include the number of people you have spoken to, the range of topics, and the outcome.\n\nYou can also make your answer clear by rating yourself from 1 - 10 on your public speaking skills.  If you have any formal training in public speaking, be sure to mention that as well.", "\"I've spoken in front of large groups of people within my previous organization and my community.  While I wouldn't say that I'm an expert, I certainly do not have stage fright when it is time to present.  I would enjoy gaining more exposure to public speaking and delivering presentations.\"", "\"My public speaking experience is minimal; however, I am currently working on improving my skills.  I attend toastmaster events and volunteer to lead monthly meetings within my organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Tell me about your most successful leadership experience.", "answers": ["As a board chairman, you take on a leadership role for your organization. You make important decisions about your organization's services, programs, resources, and most importantly, you work to fulfill the organization's mission and goals. The interviewer would like to hear about a successful leadership experience you experienced. Your response should explain what made the experience successful. If you don't have an example involving you as the leader, share an experience about a leader you've worked with.  Your response will tell the interviewer what you deem as successful leadership and give them an idea of the leadership traits you will bring to the organization.", "\"One of my favorite leadership experiences occurred while working as a manager in an HR department.  The staff had experienced significant turnover, which resulted in low morale, confusion on responsibilities, and minimal team effort.  Once I assumed my role, I prioritized identifying and understanding the issues, gathered input from employees, and developed training opportunities. After my first year, morale improved, and employees felt confident in performing their duties.\"", "\"My previous boss was one of the best leadership experiences I've had.  She made every employee feel valued and coached us for more complex roles in the company.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Describe what you have done to achieve a personal goal.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can set a goal and achieve it!  As a board chairman, this is the essence of what you will do for the organization.   Tell the interviewer about a significant goal you set and what you did to achieve it.  This can be career-related or personal but make sure your example highlights your hard work, perseverance, sacrifice, and dedication!", "\"One of the biggest personal goals I achieved was earning my Master's degree.  I wanted to dive deeper into my area of expertise and set a goal of earning my graduate degree to gain specialized knowledge and advance in my career field.  I attended classes while working a full-time job which made earning my degree feel even more special considering the hard work and sacrifices it took.\"", "\"After being hired in my current job, I set a personal goal to be promoted to a supervisory position within 2 years.  I knew it would be challenging, but I dedicated my free time to learning more about the business, taking on challenging projects, and mentoring other leaders in the company.  I was able to build my supervisory skills and knowledge, and right around the 2-year mark I was promoted to a supervisor.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Tell me about your board experience.", "answers": ["Serving on a board comes with a host of responsibilities, from monitoring finances to spreading the word about the organization, and experience is often gained by serving on other boards.  The interviewer wants to know if you have previous board experience.  If you do, share your experience with the interviewer and make sure you highlight your specific experience relative to the areas listed in the board chairman job description.  \n\nIf you don't have experience, feel free to share any experience you may have that is similar to serving on a board, such as leadership positions or serving on committees.", "\"I currently hold a leadership position where I have similar responsibilities in my organization.  I plan to bring this experience and build on it as a board chairman for your organization.\"", "\"I currently serve on my neighborhood association's committee.  We hold regular meetings to address issues within the community and decide on ways to improve our neighborhood.  From this experience, I've been able to hone my public speaking skills and decision-making skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How do you handle difficult personalities?", "answers": ["Working with other people isn't always the pleasant experience we hope it will be.  Whether it is a co-worker or someone from outside of the agency, there may be times when you encounter someone with a difficult personality.  The interviewer wants to know how you handle these types of personalities and your ability to work with all types of people.  Give an example of a time when this occurred and in your response, show the interviewer that you can remain professional, understanding, and patient.", "\"I can recall a time where I worked with a difficult co-worker.  This individual had become disgruntled after being passed over for a promotion, so their interactions with others became less than pleasant.  Even though it was a challenge to work with this person, I could empathize with how they might feel after not being promoted.  Perhaps they needed the extra money for their family, or they worked really hard in hopes of earning it, which can be frustrating.  In my interactions with this person, I continued to be professional and kept my focus on getting the job done instead of taking their behavior personally.\"", "\"When dealing with difficult personalities, I stick to the phrase 'kill them with kindness.'\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Describe your time management skills.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about your ability to manage your time and meet deadlines. Discuss how you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once. Think about how you manage your projects and daily tasks and how those will help you succeed in your role as a board chairman.", "\"I manage my time by exercising the idea of 'time-blocking.' This approach means that I won't incessantly check my email; instead, I will allow myself to return emails in 30-minute time blocks, four times per day. Setting calendar alerts and personal deadlines for myself has also helped a lot.\"", "\"I manage my priorities by creating a list of things that I need to accomplish. This helps me stay on task and never miss a deadline.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Describe your experience with legal and financial documents.", "answers": ["Board members must know how to read financial statements and legal documents to comply with laws and regulations.  Share your experience with these types of documents with the interviewer.  If you don't have significant experience, you can also share any education you've had pertaining to them.", "\"As a financial analyst, I have over 5 years of experience with financial and legal documents.  I've been responsible for interpreting the information to other managers and have been told that I do a good job explaining information in a way that is easy to understand.\"", "\"While I don't have a lot of experience with financial and legal documents, I did have some exposure during my undergraduate studies.  In my business class, we learned about financial documents, so I do know what they entail.  Immediately upon assuming my role as board chairman, I will dedicate my extra time to learning how to read financial statements and the legal requirements that we must comply with.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How do you build effective relationships?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how well you value and build relationships. Share how you play an active role in nurturing your current relationships. Also, talk to the interviewer about your strategy for building strong and valuable relationships.", "\"My personal and professional relationships are built on trust and good communication. Being trustworthy with others allows them to feel comfortable sharing information with you and knowing you'll do the same. I most definitely value my relationships and am sure to nurture those relationships as much as possible.\"", "\"I have strong relationships with my clients and customers. I treat them with respect and am sure to utilize their feedback in ways that make myself and the organization better.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How do you manage stressful situations?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you are someone who can handle stress on the job. Explain how you manage stressful times and your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I always remain calm and look for ways to be more efficient. For instance, if there is an unexpected deadline, I will determine what can be done to meet the deadline. I will write down the steps to ensure successful completion and delegate a few tasks if necessary. In brief, I am always ready to adjust my approach because stressful situations are bound to occur in a professional environment.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, including a board chairman, and I embrace it to the fullest. I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": ["This question is often a challenge for individuals to respond to when they are unsure or can't articulate how they can benefit the company. If you can't think of ways that you are unique, ask a few friends or family members what sets you apart from other people. Their observations may help you understand how you are perceived. It is also a good idea to think about the highlights of previous job performance reviews. If a supervisor praised you on a particular area that you do well or received recognition for making a significant impact on a project, feel free to mention this in your response if it relates to the expectations of a board chairman. \n\nPerhaps you already know what sets you apart! Your answer could include any industry accolades, exceptional achievements, additional industry-related training, a second language, or your involvement in the community. Don't be afraid to brag about yourself a bit. In an interview, you are your most influential advocate.", "\"You should hire me because I am unlike anyone else you have interviewed before. When I started my current company, I was the youngest human resources professional they had ever hired. That didn't stop me from being promoted to a leadership role shortly after being hired. I am dedicated to my craft and will commit myself to take at least one business development or leadership-related workshop every business quarter. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\"", "\"Your mission to do XYZ is one that I am incredibly passionate about.  You should hire me because I will be fully dedicated to using my network, skills, and knowledge to drive your organization closer to meeting your overall goals.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How do you handle conflict with other employees or board members?", "answers": ["In any work environment, there are times when conflict may arise.  The interviewer wants to know how well you handle conflict and your ability to respond professionally in these instances.  Provide an example of a conflict you were involved in and share details such as the nature of the problem, how you handled it, and the outcome.  If you don't have an example, describe how you would respond in this type of situation.", "\"I always handle conflict by first understanding the issue because tension can escalate when there is confusion.   I keep my communication professional and raise the issue to higher levels of management if no resolution can be made by talking through the issue with my co-worker.\"", "\"I consider myself a team player.  I haven't been faced with a conflict with other employees, but if I did, I would work with them instead of against them to find common ground.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Have you ever had to fire anyone? How did you feel about that?", "answers": ["A necessary yet uncomfortable part of any supervisory role is having to fire someone who is not meeting the expectations of the position and/or company.  The interviewer wants to know if you have experience firing employees and your comfort level in doing so.  If you've never fired anyone, that's ok.  Share how you would approach the situation if the need should arise.", "\"I've had to fire several employees over the years, and it never gets any easier.  While it may be uncomfortable for me, it's important to adhere to the company's rules.  Any time that I've fired someone, I've been professional and made sure that they fully understand the reason for termination and offered words of advice for the future of their career.\"", "\"Fortunately, I've never had to fire anyone from a job.  However, I am comfortable having these difficult conversations and will remain stern yet empathetic when doing so.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How do you evaluate the performance of others?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know the methods or thought processes you use to evaluate the performance of others.  In your response, share how you factor in performance-based\n expectations to determine how well an employee or board member performs.  In addition to their specific job duties, some areas to mention can include:\n\n-Reliability\n-Teamwork\n-Knowledge\n-Problem-solving skills\n-Compliance\n-Customer service\n-Representing the organization", "\"I evaluate the performance of others based on their ability to perform their duties successfully and on time with minimal assistance.  I also factor in their reliability and team contributions.  If an employee has put in the effort to improve their skills and knowledge, this is also important to consider.\"", "\"I evaluate the performance of others by the effort they put into doing their job.  Projects can be completed by doing the bare minimum, but it is evident when an employee goes above and beyond to make a good project great.  These are the things I consider when evaluating performance.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How quickly do you make decisions? Give me an example.", "answers": ["Making the right decision can be time-consuming as you gather details and weigh your options.  However, sometimes you don't have the time to ponder!  The interviewer wants to know how long you take to make sound decisions.  If you are someone who takes a little longer, share why it takes you some time to make decisions.  Perhaps you want to gather as much information as possible.  Or you want to allow time to consider the consequences of your decisions.  \n\nIf you are someone who can make decisions quickly, share your decision-making method and how you've been successful at doing so.", "\"I've never been someone who takes a long time to make decisions.  As long as you have the information you need to make an informed decision, pondering over it will only cause you to doubt your decision.  I like to make decisions quickly and move forward.\"", "\"My previous co-workers have told me that I am very thorough when I make decisions.  My decision-making process consists of obtaining pertinent details, considering outcomes, and choosing the option that best aligns with the company's needs.  This has allowed me to make good decisions in the past.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Tell me about a time when you influenced the outcome of a project by taking a leadership role.", "answers": ["Leadership means being able to influence people and outcomes in any situation.  Describe a time when you used your leadership skills to positively impact the outcome of a project.  Share what the project entailed and what you did to help advance the project.  Keep in mind that your example can be about a time you were officially in a leadership role or a time when you stepped up and assumed a leadership role in a group.  Either example should demonstrate the leadership abilities the organization is seeking in a board chairperson.", "\"In a previous role, I was assigned to a group that was tasked with helping a client restructure their organization.  There was no identified project leader, so we lacked accountability with staying on task and meeting milestones.  Because I was dedicated to completing the project successfully, I assumed the leadership role in the group. I did check-ins with the team to encourage open communication and ensure we were on schedule to meet the deadline.  We were able to meet the client's needs successfully and on time, and everyone appreciated my effort in keeping us all on schedule.\"", "\"A good leader can influence an outcome by being a good communicator, a team player, and keeping their focus on the organization's mission.  I feel that I do these things every day and will be committed to doing the same for your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What would other co-workers or board members say about your work ethic or character?", "answers": ["Being a board chairman means working on a unique leadership team, all working towards a common goal.  The interviewer wants to know what kind of team member you will be.  Think about the qualities that make a good board chairman.  You'll likely identify a few that you possess! Share what previous co-workers or board members have said about your work ethic and demonstrate how these qualities align with the requirements of a board chairman.", "\"My previous co-workers would say that I am reliable and flexible.  I've worked on projects where I've had to wear many hats due to a shortage of employees, and my co-workers always complimented me on my ability to switch gears but remain focused on the project outcomes.\"", "\"My co-workers would say I am honest, dedicated, and a team player.  I take my job seriously as I know others are relying on me to do my part.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What three words would you use to describe yourself?", "answers": ["For this question, think about the qualities or requirements needed to fulfill the role of board chairman.  Then, think about your own qualities that align with these qualities.  Perhaps you are driven, ambitious, philanthropic, selfless, dedicated, honest, or possess other characteristics that describe who you are. Ultimately, you want to show the interviewer how you possess the qualities they are seeking in a good board chairperson and member of their team.", "\"I would describe myself as someone reliable, committed, and trustworthy.  I pride myself on building successful client relationships, and these are the qualities that have aided in me doing so.  I think my references will agree.\"", "\"I would definitely say that I am honest, ambitious, and professional.  In my opinion, these are also the characteristics of a good board chairman.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "How would you rate your communication skills?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know your communication skill level.  As a board chairman, you will communicate with individuals in and outside of the organization, so this is an important skill. Share your communication skill level for verbal and written communication as this covers speaking in public, talking on the phone, emails, and other forms of communication typically done in an organization.\n\nYou can also make your answer clear by rating yourself from 1 - 10 on your communication skills.  If you have any formal training, be sure to mention that as well.", "\"I would rate my communication skills as a 9.  There is always room for improvement, but I have developed strong communication skills over the years by being professional, explaining things clearly and thoroughly, and thinking before I speak.  I have spoken in front of groups of all sizes, and email is a regular part of my duties.\"", "\"My communication skills are an 8.  Speaking in front of large groups is the one area I struggle in, but I would love the opportunity to join an organization where I can build my skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What fundraising experience do you have?", "answers": ["Fundraising is a key part of serving on a board.  It is used to raise funds for an organization and raise awareness about a particular cause.  Share any fundraising experience you may have with the interviewer.  This might include planning, organizing, managing the events, or spreading the word about it in the community.", "\"I've contributed to fundraising events by working on the planning committee.  I made decisions on logistics, marketing, and scheduling.\"", "\"My fundraising experience comes from my effort in trying to help raise funds for cancer awareness events.  I've run in races, sold items, and help spread the word through social media platforms.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "Why are you the best board chairman for us?", "answers": ["This question is your opportunity to shine!  Think about the job description and requirements of the board chairman and think about how your skills and knowledge align with what the organization is seeking.  Also, think about your reason for applying to be a board chairman. Share how your attributes align perfectly for the role and express your desire to move the organization's mission forward.  Show that you have what it takes and that you are passionate about it!", "\"I believe I am the best board chairman for you because I am passionate about your mission to do XYZ.  I've built a solid background in finance and a diverse network of business professionals that will allow me to exceed the expectations of this role.  I also understand that this role requires a time commitment that I am committed to fulfilling.\"", "\"I've done my research about your organization, and my background and career goals aligns perfectly for a role as a board chairman.  I know that I'll be able to make a positive impact when it comes to your projects focused on XYZ.\""]}, {"topic": "Board+Chairman", "question": "What strategies do you use to manage your time?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of tools you use to stay on task and meet deadlines. Discuss how you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once. Think about how you manage your projects and daily tasks and how those will help you succeed in your role as a board chairman.", "\"I manage my time by using a calendar to keep track of meetings and deadlines. I also set alerts to notify me when these dates and times are approaching.  This allows me to prepare ahead of time and ensure I never miss a deadline.\"", "\"I manage my time by exercising the idea of 'time-blocking.' This approach means that I won't incessantly check my email; instead, I will allow myself to return emails in 30-minute time blocks, four times per day.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "Describe a time when you had to make a decision where there was no perfect outcome.", "answers": ["Decisions don't always result in a perfect outcome. As a nurse, you know that making choices around health means that sometimes you're choosing between two unpleasant outcomes. However, a decision still needs to be made. The interviewer wants to know how you triage situations to arrive at the best conclusion. Showcase your critical thinking skills while providing a story-based example of when you faced a related scenario.", "\"When faced with minimal positive outcomes, I try to make decisions based on which will cause the least amount of damage. For instance, during COVID, my unit shut down, and the hospital wanted to pull the GI nurses to the COVID units. It was the beginning of COVID, and no vaccinations were available. Also, the hospital was not providing alternate assignments to the nursing staff. I am the primary caregiver for my elderly parents, who wear oxygen. I loved working at my job in GI and had been there for ten years, and I needed the income to take care of my parents. I faced a difficult situation with no actual ideal outcome. I went to HR, but everyone was clamoring for better assignments. The option of quitting was terrifying, but the prospect of bringing COVID home to my parents was even more frightening. I ended up resigning from my position after a two-week notice. Looking back at the decision, I am glad that I did what it took to protect my parents. They remained healthy through COVID, and I quickly secured new employment.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "What does compassionate care mean to you?", "answers": ["Showing empathy to those suffering and supporting them with dignity and respect is integral in nursing care. Compassion is the process of advocating for a patient's well-being while trying to find solutions to their suffering. Interviewers are looking for evidence of your compassion in your response. They also want to see that your approach to compassionate care aligns with that of the facility.", "\"Compassionate care is synonymous with my nursing practice. I want to deliver exceptional physical care and extraordinary emotional care at the same time. My philosophy is that we cannot separate the mind from the body, and outcomes are better when we have high regard for both. I want the patient to believe that they have dignity and deserve respect no matter what is unfolding. Compassionate care combines medical and emotional care that allows the patient to feel safe and valued while receiving extraordinary medical attention. Should I be chosen for this nursing position, I will show compassionate care by acting as a courageous advocate for my patient.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you demonstrate compassionate care in nursing?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know precisely how you demonstrate compassion in your daily work. When you respond, rather than simply list the 6 C's of compassionate care, show the interviewer that you have a personal philosophy that you implement on the job. Share your philosophy and discuss how you incorporate compassionate care principles into the daily care of patients.", "\"I believe in respectful communication, professional boundaries, and ensuring my patients feel safe in my care. I take the time to understand my patients' medical reports, and then I ask the patient what I can do or improve on to ensure they are getting the best care. A significant component to delivering compassionate care is also to be culturally aware.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "Why is compassionate caring necessary in nursing?", "answers": ["As the saying goes, people may not remember what you say, but they always remember how you made them feel. A nurse can graduate at the top of their class and have outstanding technical skills, but without compassion, they are not as effective as they could be.  \n\nNurses must be competent and provide compassionate care across all healthcare settings; however, competency does not guarantee compassion, and the interviewer is looking for evidence that you possess both. Discuss why you believe compassionate care is a critical approach and provide details on how you deliver compassionate care in nursing.", "\"Compassionate care combines trust, dignity, respect and more with the patient, their families, and the expanded healthcare team. For me, compassion and empathy are intertwined and feel like the foundational base for a trusting patient/nurse relationship. When I bond with my patient compassionately and professionally, communication is more open, creating a better understanding of their needs. The more I understand, the better care I deliver.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "What do you know about our facility and team culture?", "answers": ["If you didn't do your homework on the facility before your interview, it would become evident with a question like this! This question deserves a specific response tailored to each organization with which you are interviewing. Before the meeting, take some time to look at the facility or system you are applying to work in. Know their mission statement, who they serve, if they are public or private, and more. You can discover helpful information on Healthgrades.com.", "\"I took time to research Organization ABC before our meeting today, and found some exciting information. I especially appreciate your organization's commitment to having at least 80% BSN or better by 2025. The nursing leadership is also impressive, and I've read several of Dr. Doctor's articles on WebMD. Also, I have been following the organization's social media accounts since I graduated from nursing school and have noticed a strong correlation between patient care and commitment to the community. On the lighter side, I see that your teams participate in a marathon every year, raising funds for charity. This initiative is one I would love to participate in as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "If hired to join our nursing team, what will you accomplish in the first 30 days?", "answers": ["Just like you must prepare information about the hiring company, you must attend your interview prepared to discuss what you will achieve if hired. Your first 30 days goals should align with the mission of the organization and your accountabilities in this nursing role. \n\nInclude personal and professional goals at work such as getting to know your peers, possibly joining a work-based social group to meet people, take advantage of Continuing Education Units (CEU) or even enroll in a course. Show the interviewer that you are prepared to invest in their organization, your new team, and in yourself.", "\"I am interested in exploring everything that this organization has to offer. In my first 30 days, I expect to attend hospital-wide orientation and then a unit orientation. I would be eager to meet my new co-workers on my unit, and I would love to get involved in a hospital project such as a focus group or club. Aside from these team-building activities, I would make a strong impression on my new team by absorbing their advice and observing how my co-workers collaborate smoothly during a shift. Continued education is important to me, so I would speak with HR about the best approach to gaining CEU's. I also heard this facility has a great medical library, and I cannot wait to explore it!\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you approach taking responsibility for your mistakes?", "answers": ["Everyone makes mistakes, and the focus of your response is not to show perfection. The interviewer wants to know how you handle it when you have made an error. \n\nMistakes can be embarrassing; however, there are healthy ways to admit you've done something wrong and repair the situation. Show the interviewer that you deal with mistakes in a way that leads to a resolution vs. ignoring the error or making it worse.", "\"When I discover that I've made a mistake, I sort my emotions, and then I go about fixing the situation. This action includes admitting my mistake to the people who need to know and asking for feedback to make it right. I will assess who my error has impacted and if I need to apologize to anyone. It's important that when I make an error, I repair the situation thoroughly, regardless of whether this may bruise my ego or make me feel vulnerable.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "What does having a strong work ethic mean to you?", "answers": ["Work ethic is 'the principle that hard work is intrinsically virtuous or worthy of reward.' When you value the concept of having a solid work ethic, you are showing that you place value in delivering high-quality work. \n\nHaving a solid work ethic is essential in any job and extremely important in healthcare. People's lives depend on your dedication as a nurse to going above and beyond for the best possible outcome. The interviewer wants to see that you have a strong inner compass that guides you to deliver work considered 'virtuous' and 'worthy of reward.' Provide evidence that you are committed to doing a terrific job every day.", "\"To me, having a strong work ethic means taking a task and doing it incredibly well, no matter the circumstances. I have been a nurse for ten years, and every day I deliver work that makes me feel proud. I value my ability to make a difference in the lives of my patients, and I strive to honor my profession by doing my best every day.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "What is your approach to teamwork?", "answers": ["Working on a team is not the most suitable environment for everyone; however, as a nurse, you must collaborate with your healthcare team at all times. The interviewer wants to know that you value teamwork and how you operate in a team setting. Talk about how you support your team and describe how you communicate with others, ensuring your team moves as one cohesive group.", "\"One of the foundational principles to successful healthcare is teamwork. I need to be a strong team member to other nurses, various healthcare disciplines, patients, and families. My approach to teamwork includes supporting my leadership team and trusting them to make the best decisions possible. I follow the groups' decisions unless they fail to align with my morals or healthcare philosophy. I do not take any conflict personally, and I always view a crisis as an opportunity to rise. Sometimes, nursing brings a chaotic work environment with opinions and viewpoints coming from many directions. As an avid team player, I make it my business to know the scope of my practice and practice within those boundaries when things are busy on the floor.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "Describe how your work ethic extends to your everyday life.", "answers": ["Many psychologists and writers have expressed, 'the best predictor of future behavior is past behavior.' This adage can also go for how closely a person's actions align inside and outside of work. \n\nThe interviewer is looking for patterns in your behavior and actions. For instance, if you are always late in your personal life, it is unlikely you are always on time for work. Talk about your work ethic and discuss how your ethics are in alignment personally and professionally.", "\"I lead my personal and professional life based on my values of integrity and responsibility. My work ethic extends to my everyday life in each action and decision, no matter how large or small. I display this by being on time for all of my commitments inside and outside of the workplace. I complete tasks, no matter how unpleasant, because they need to get done. I also do what I say that I will do, being a person of my word. I am a caregiver even outside of my nursing career. I help others, give what I can, and take only what I need.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you respond when a patient asks for your help with a delicate situation?", "answers": ["Helping a patient with a delicate or sensitive situation requires good problem-solving skills paired with empathy. As a nurse, it is easy to react to most patient's clinical problems; however, with this question, the interviewer wants insight into how you approach problem-solving when an empathetic approach is required. \n\nExpress that you would offer genuine help rather than give generic comfort to a patient who truly needs you. Show that you can handle potentially uncomfortable situations with poise and professionalism. If you have experienced a similar scenario, consider telling a brief story that highlights your ability to be empathetic when needed.", "\"I love the saying, 'healing begins when people feel heard.' Whether or not I can help to solve the issue, I am always willing to listen. Sometimes people just need to be heard. If a patient comes to me with a problem that may be sensitive, I will give them my full attention. I work to understand what is concerning them. If it's appropriate, I will offer suggestions on how to address the situation. I use the SOAPIER approach (Subjective, Objective, Assessment, Planning, Implementing, Evaluating, Reassessing) for nearly every problem. I know this approach is often used in healthcare, and for good reason as it works for just about every problem, even situations where I need to extend empathy while also helping to problem-solve.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you handle it when a workplace situation makes you feel angry or frustrated?", "answers": ["Feelings of anger or frustration are bound to occur when working in a healthcare environment where situations can become hectic or high-pressure. Yet, not everyone has the skill set to handle those feelings well. As a skilled nurse, what differentiates you is the emotional intelligence you possess, allowing you to react to feelings of anger appropriately.\n\nEveryone feels angry from time to time. When you respond, be honest and show that you are an authentic person rather than stating that you never feel angry. The interviewer is looking for evidence that can deal with conflict in a healthy way. If you have experienced a relatable situation, consider telling a brief story highlighting your ability to react to feelings of anger or frustration appropriately.", "\"I continually work on building my EQ, including my ability to handle feelings of frustration or anger in an emotionally intelligent way. I used to work with a physician who would say, 'when emotions run high, intelligence runs low.' When facing a situation where emotions run high, I try to sort out my feelings and stay focused on finding a solution. Using this approach, I avoid taking a situation personally and work towards an outcome that benefits everyone. Reacting poorly or having an outburst is not an option because the team and the patients suffer, and the outcome is never positive. I choose to react in a manner that benefits everyone and reflects well on my team and me.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you approach delivering sensitive or discouraging news?", "answers": ["Nursing is front-line, demanding work, and you often deal with families and patients in crisis. Typically, it is not the nurse's responsibility to deliver sensitive or discouraging news about lab work or a diagnosis, for instance. However, you may face situations like telling someone their loved one was unexpectedly taken to surgery. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about your approach to delivering news that may be sensitive or discouraging. Show that you are professional and empathetic when communicating sensitive information to others. If you have experienced a situation like this, consider including a story that showcases your approach.", "\"Delivering sensitive or discouraging news is part of my responsibility as a nurse, and I must do this in a way that is professional yet shows empathy toward the person receiving the news. First, I make certain that it's my news to tell and that I have the authority and responsibility to deliver the information. If it's my information to deliver, I do not avoid that responsibility. I center myself and think of the situation from the other person's perspective. When possible, I make certain that I schedule time so I do not have to leave abruptly after delivering the news. I stay in their space and be silent but present if needed. The presence of someone else can be very comforting to a person feeling anxious or upset after receiving sensitive news.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you handle it when an interpersonal conflict arises in your unit?", "answers": ["Nursing is a challenging enough career, and nobody wants a loose cannon or an icy individual on their unit. When co-workers exhibit unhealthy emotional responses to conflict, that energy creates lasting damage. It can make others feel uncomfortable, take sides, or gossip, plummeting team morale. \n\nThe interviewer wants to know that you can handle interpersonal conflict without exploding or imploding. Show that you are a nurse with emotional intelligence, and you can experience conflict at work without the situation impacting your job performance.", "\"Of course, I would like to say that I react to interpersonal conflict wonderfully and effectively 100% of the time, but that's not realistic. I actively work to live my life on a pretty even keel emotionally. That is, I don't veer too widely off-center with my emotions. This approach allows me to handle let-downs, conflict, and other problems with balance instead of reeling wildly and being reactionary. I have learned to address interpersonal conflicts right away so they do not fester and become inflated. For instance, I might ask the person. 'Hey, I feel a strain between us, and I'd like to talk it over. Is now a good time?' I use 'I' statements and own my feelings. I don't go down the 'you make me feel' route because that sounds accusatory. I think about the outcome I'd like to achieve and remain focused on that. I believe that open conversations are important, and they are the foundation to building a healthy team.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you deal with differences of opinion when working among a team of healthcare providers?", "answers": ["As a nurse, much of your job requires coming to a consensus with your team of healthcare professionals on a patient care approach and then enthusiastically carrying out that plan. Some team members who do not support the final decision may grumble and be reluctant. They may even be verbal about the outcome in a very public way. This behavior can destroy morale and undermine the function of a team. \n\nInterviewers seek nursing candidates who can confidently present and advocate for their best ideas. They also seek nurses who can be accepting and supportive when other people's ideas are chosen. The interviewer wants to know that you understand the importance of supporting team-based decisions, even if you have a difference of opinion. Consider a time when your team was divided and could not come to a consensus.", "\"A high-functioning healthcare team will have diverse opinions and ideas. This diversity in opinion can make it tough to ensure that everyone agrees on the same approach at all times. I also understand it takes a lot of time and effort to build a cohesive team. For instance, thinking back to the rock tumbler I had as a child. It took a lot of loud noise and stones bumping up against each other to create beautiful gemstones. Just because five people are in the same room doesn't mean they are a team. When I am facing a difference of opinion, I take the time to understand how my team members are thinking and how they have reached their preferred decision. If I can see that the consensus leans toward the best outcome for the team, unit, facility, and most of all, the patient, I will set my idea aside and enthusiastically contribute to the team.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "How do you handle communicating with an upset patient?", "answers": ["As a nurse, it takes a lot of emotional intelligence, empathy, and people skills to negotiate your way through a situation involving an upset patient. Although this is a common situation to experience as a healthcare professional, it does not mean accepting abusive behaviors. The interviewer is looking for evidence that you can handle conflict-based situations without overreacting or causing the problem to worsen. Show that you understand the importance of responding to an upset patient quickly, authentically, and in a facility-centered way.", "\"Nursing is hard work, and I believe that all healthcare professionals deserve respectful communication. If I felt verbally abused or disrespected, I would remove myself from the situation and bring the issue to my immediate supervisor. A patient will lash out in most instances due to pain, grief, confusion, or other strong emotions. I understand that and do not take it personally. I don't think it's constructive to ignore situations like this and go about the day. This approach could invalidate a patient or a patients' family and make them more isolated. If I were at fault for a situation that caused a patient to feel angry, I would earnestly and honestly apologize and ask what I can do to resolve their concerns.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "Talk about a problem you faced at work and how you applied critical thinking to address the situation.", "answers": ["Critical thinking is the ability to solve problems and make the best decisions based on your expertise. Nursing requires you to constantly showcase your critical thinking skills since you face unique situations every day. At the same time, you must make decisions and take actions consistent with regulations in your region.\n\nSince the interviewer asks you to tell them about a time when you faced a problem, it's essential to use a real-life example when you respond. Show the interviewer that you are a strong critical thinker and that your approach to problem-solving aligns with their facility's values.", "\"A few months ago, I smelled alcohol on a co-worker's breath during the morning report. The laws around practicing healthcare while intoxicated are clear - it's illegal. Aside from the legalities, the nurse could have caused harm to others or herself. I also knew that I needed to protect our facility from potential mistakes or malpractice. Although it was awkward, I pulled my co-worker aside, and I spoke frankly to her. I mentioned that she smelled like alcohol, and I was concerned for both her and our patients. She told me she had been out at a bachelorette party late the night before then came in for her morning shift. She agreed to go to our nursing manager, admit the situation, and then go home. Ultimately, my approach encouraged the best outcome for everyone. Since she went home, my co-worker didn't lose her license, and there was no risk of potential harm due to impairment. As a nurse, I encounter daily problems to solve. My role is a practice-based discipline of higher-level thinking to ensure that I deliver safe care to all patients.\""]}, {"topic": "Nursing+Soft+Skills", "question": "Please walk us through your decision-making process.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can assess a situation, weigh your options, decide on a course of action, and implement a solution confidently. As a nurse, when you need to make an important decision, it's essential that you critically think through the scenario and the outcome. You certainly do not make decisions based on a 'gut instinct,' and you do not delay important decisions because you need to do extensive research. You also know that, although you may need the right people to weigh in before you make a decision, asking a multitude of team members for their opinion is not a resourceful approach. Walk the interviewer through your decision-making process and show them that your approach is a good fit for their work environment.", "\"A career in nursing has been great to me in many ways. It has given me a job that I love and has provided me with an exceptional framework for decision-making. When facing an important decision, I sort out my emotions first because high emotions tend to hinder intelligent decisions. Then, I look at the subjective information and the objective information. I assess the situation, develop a plan, implement it, and then evaluate the outcome. If my decision did not achieve the desired result, I re-evaluate and repeat the process until I achieve the best outcome.\""]}]